■
本字幕由ShinY深影字幕组原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址http://shinybbs.net
■
-=ShinY-深影字幕组=-
深影翻翻：  Ruice 兔兔 紫流苏 金 福川
■
-=ShinY-深影字幕组=-
校对人员：  兔兔   总监： 地球happy   后期&特效： 大逋
我必须马上见他! 求你了!
I must see him now! Please!
大侦探波罗探案集
第11季第3集 第三个女郎
先生 一位年轻的女士登门拜访
A young lady has called in, sir.
这个时间我不见客的 乔治 不见
I do not see people at this hour, George. Non.
是的 先生
No, sir.
她有没有说为什么想见我?
Does she give a reason for wishing to see me?
她说奥利弗夫人推荐了您 先生
She says Mrs Oliver recommended you, sir.
说是她可能杀了人
It's about a murder she might have committed.
可能杀了人? 你的意思是她自己不知道?
Might have committed? You mean she does not know?
这个理由并不充分 乔治
This is not very satisfactory, George.
不过另一方面 事情也许会很有趣
But, on the other hand, it might be interesting.
麻烦你 帮我换衣服
Help me to dress, s'il vous plat.
谢谢 等等
Merci. Moment.
好了
Bon.
小姐 这边请
This way, miss.
小姐 你好
Bonjour, mademoiselle.
我听说您与奥利弗夫人相熟
I hear you are acquainted with Madame Oliver.
您想来见我? 您请坐
You wish to see me? Sit down, I pray of you.
您是赫尔克里・波罗?
You're Hercule Poirot?
如假包换
Assuredly.
那个有名的侦探?
The famous detective?
我算是小有名气吧 是的
Some people have heard my name, oui.
那么 我该如何为您效劳呢 小姐?
Now, how may I help you, mademoiselle?
我的男仆说您可能杀了人
My manservant mentioned a murder that you might have committed.
您认为我很可笑
You find me amusing.
不 绝无此意 小姐
No, not at all, mademoiselle,
不过如果杀了人 自己知道才正常
but it is normal to know if one has committed a murder.
不过我并不...正常 您看不出来吗?
But I'm not... normal. Can't you see that?
小姐 我眼前所见的
I see only what is before me, mademoiselle.
只有一位焦急不安的年轻女子
A young lady who is anxious.
能跟我说说您想象中的这起谋杀案吗...
So, would you like to tell me about this murder that you imagine you...
我真不该来的 我以为您也许能理解
It was a mistake to come here. I thought you might understand.
我以为您也许能救我一命
I thought you might be able to save me.
怎么救呢 小姐?
From what, mademoiselle?
没什么 已经无所谓了 到此为止
Nothing. It doesn't matter now. It's done.
还有...你太老了!
Besides... you're too old!
太老了?
Too old?
真是伤人!
How hurtful!
不 不 没关系的 夫人
No, no, no, not at all, madame.
女孩子就是这样
Girls are like that.
她们觉得过了三十五岁的人都只剩半条命
Anyone over 35 they think is half dead.
女孩子都不理智 您必须认识到这一点
They've no sense, girls. You must realise that.
不过您为什么建议她来拜访我?
But why did you suggest she visit me?
她认为有桩谋杀案
She thought there'd been a murder.
事情在哪儿发生?
Where was this?
- 谋杀案? - 不 是你们的对话
- The murder? - No, the conversation.
在这儿 就在电梯里
It was here, in the lift.
她完全心慌意乱了 想找愿意倾听的人
She was completely distraught, in need of a sympathetic ear.
那么 您在这部电梯里遇到了这个陌生的女孩
So, you meet in this lift this girl who is a stranger
而她也随即跟您坦白她杀了人?
and immediately she confesses to a murder?
是的 听起来很像我小说里的桥段是吗?
Yes, it does sound like the plot of one of my novels, doesn't it?
不过 波罗先生 我昨晚在一场舞会上见过她
But you see, Monsieur Poirot, I'd met her before. Last night, at a party.
就在楼上她们的公寓里
Upstairs in their flat.
- 她是第三个女孩 - 第三个女孩?
- She was the third girl. - The third girl?
您也知道如今这世道
Well, you know how it is these days.
一个女孩租下一整套公寓 她的朋友再合租
One girl takes a lease on a flat, her friend joins her,
其中第二好的房间 租金会少点
in the second-best bedroom, paying less rent,
然后再找人租剩下的房间
then they find somebody for the room that's left.
第三个女孩 就是她了
The third girl. That was her.
啊 第三个女孩 再多说一点舞会的事吧
Ah, the third girl. Tell to me more about this party.
她们闹得吵吵嚷嚷
They were making such a terrible racket.
我根本无法写作 于是我决定和她们一道
Totally impossible to work. So, I decided to join them.
那场舞会是为了庆祝第一个女孩的生日
It was a party to celebrate the first girl's birthday.
她是某个商人的秘书
She's secretary to some businessman or other.
叫克劳迪娅・瑞斯・霍兰德
Claudia Reece-Holland.
非常漂亮 很能干
Very pretty, very efficient.
她就是那种能委以重任的姑娘
Just the sort of girl you need for a tricky job.
第二个女孩大约是叫弗朗西丝吧
The second girl was Frances something or other.
崇尚艺术 是个女演员
Very arty. Works as an actress.
她看上去十分友善...只是有点矫揉造作
She seemed nice enough... if a little artificial.
然后就是第三个女孩 她似乎受了冷落
And then there was the third girl, looking somewhat left out,
好像与其他人相处得不太融洽
as if she didn't quite fit in.
事实上 唯一一次她活跃起来
In fact, the only time she came to life
正是那个"孔雀"出现的时候
was when the peacock arrived.
夫人 您说的"孔雀"是什么?
Madame, what is this peacock?
是了 "孔雀" 至少他给我的感觉是如此
Yes, the peacock. Well, at least that's what he reminded me of.
他是个画家 大卫・贝克
He's a painter. David Baker.
特别浮夸 很...脂粉气
Very flamboyant, quite... effete,
尽管如此 他一到场就不停地
though he was making eyes at the third girl
朝第三个女孩暗送秋波
from the moment he arrived.
第三个女孩 她的名字是?
This third girl, how does she call herself?
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克
Norma Restarick.
今天早晨您遇到了诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐
This morning you meet Mademoiselle Norma Restarick,
她向您坦白了杀人一事
and she confesses to a murder.
告诉我 夫人 是谁被杀害了?
Tell me, madame, who has been murdered?
她没说
Well, she didn't say.
她显得疑惑而又不安
She seemed confused and upset.
所以我建议她来白港大厦来见您
So I suggested she pop over to Whitehaven Mansions and see you.
亲爱的夫人
Chère madame,
您碰巧知晓最近在这栋大楼里
do you know of any murder
发生过任何谋杀案吗?
that has taken place recently? In this building, peut-être?
我倒希望有留意到谋杀案呢
I rather think I'd have noticed a murder,
波罗先生 对吗?
Monsieur Poirot, don't you?
啊! 纳尔森警长来了
Ah! Inspector Nelson arrives.
也许我们有谋杀案了 夫人
Perhaps we have our murder, madame.
警管 能请你告诉纳尔森警长
Constable, will you tell the Inspector Nelson
赫尔克里・波罗也在这儿吗?
that Hercule Poirot is here?
- 好的 先生 - 有劳
- Yes, sir. - Merci.
波罗 我就猜到你可能会来
Poirot. I might have guessed you'd turn up.
纳尔森警长
Inspector Nelson.
很显然 是自杀
Took her own life, clearly.
嗯 看上去的确如此
Well, that is certainly the impression.
这位不幸的女士是谁?
Who was the unfortunate lady?
拉维尼娅・施格兰姆
Lavinia Seagram.
据发现她的门房说
According to the concierge who found her,
她已经在这里住了不少年头
she lived here for many years.
深居简出 鲜有访客...
Kept herself to herself, very few visitors...
...酒量很大
...drank a lot.
一位很不幸福的女子
A very unhappy woman.
现在请告诉我 你来此有何贵干?
Now tell me, what are you doing here?
呃...碰巧来探访一位友人
Er... Merely rendering a visit to a friend.
悲惨的人生 是吗?
A life so sad, huh?
就像她的死亡
As was her death.
- 她有没有留下遗书? - 看来没有
- Did she leave a note of suicide? - It appears not.
您允许我亲自查看一下她的公寓吗?
And will you permit that I examine for myself her apartment?
- 理由? - 仅仅出于好奇
- For what reason? - Curiosity only.
好奇 啊?
Curiosity, eh?
若您执意如此的话
Well, if you must.
多谢 噢 还有一件事 警长
Merci. Oh, one another thing, Inspector.
那位门房还知道施格兰姆小姐的其他事吗?
Did the concierge know anything more about Mademoiselle Seagram?
比如 她的故乡?
For instance, from where did she originate?
还有她搬到这里之前生活得怎么样?
Or how did she live before she came here?
- 只听说她曾经做过保姆 - 啊 谢谢
- Only that she used to work as a nanny. - Ah, merci.
"十字树篱庄园 长基 1917年
"Crosshedges, Long Basing, 1917.
最后一个快乐的夏天
The last happy summer.
A J 巴特斯比"
A J Battersby. "
施格兰姆保姆 玛丽以及诺尔玛小姐
Nanny Seagram, Mary and Mademoiselle Norma.
这就是关联
There is the connection.
那玛丽是?
And Mary?
嗯 也许是她母亲
Well, the mother, perhaps.
最后一个快乐的夏天
The last happy summer.
恐怕有些事情不对劲
I fear that there is here something strange.
诺尔玛
Norma.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
诺尔玛!
Norma!
诺尔玛... 想让我陪你坐坐吗?
Norma... would you like me to come and sit with you?
不用了 我想自己一个人
No, I'd like to be alone.
可不幸地是 我们和你摆脱不了关系了
But unfortunately, we are stuck with you.
她现在这种状况 总是嘟哝着血啊什么的
She's in such a state. She keeps muttering something about blood.
老天爷
Good Lord.
可怜的保姆
Poor Nanny.
你好 安德鲁 请到会客室来
Hello, Andrew. Come through to the drawing room.
谢谢 克劳迪娅
Thank you, Claudia.
弗朗西丝 这位是诺尔玛的父亲
Frances, this is Norma's father,
安德鲁・雷斯塔里克
Andrew Restarick.
你好吗 弗朗西丝?
How do you do, Frances?
克劳迪娅说你一直对我女儿很好 我很感激
Claudia says you've been very kind to my daughter. I'm grateful.
呃... 你说她在自己的房间里?
Er... She's in her room, you say?
有什么事让她深感困扰
There's something troubling her very deeply.
她总是念叨着什么死人还有血
She keeps talking about dead people and blood.
你们的一位邻居 保姆施格兰姆...
One of your neighbours, Nanny Seagram...
...自杀了
...has killed herself.
什么?
What?
我刚从她的公寓过来
I've just come from her apartment.
也许诺尔玛已经察觉了此事
Perhaps Norma's already found out.
自杀了? 她的老保姆?
Killed herself? Her old nanny?
也难怪她会有这番举动了
Well, no wonder she's behaving as she is.
可怜的诺尔玛
Poor Norma.
是啊 可怜的诺尔玛
Yes, poor Norma.
警察很肯定是自杀?
The police are quite certain it was suicide?
没错 他们的确是这么想的
Yes, they seem to think so.
保姆施格兰姆是个不幸福的女人
Nanny Seagram was not a happy woman.
- 我还是去和她谈谈 - 嗯
- I'd better talk to her. - Mm.
我当时在那儿
I was there.
我杀了她
I killed her.
你没对其他人说过这事吧 是吗?
You haven't said this to anyone else, have you?
我对...奥利弗夫人说了
I said something... to Mrs Oliver, I think,
还有我见过面的一位老人
and to an old man I met.
- 但是没人相信我 - 因为那不是真的
- But no-one believes me. - Because it's not true.
听着... 我想我能帮你
Look... I think I can help you.
有很多地方能帮你摆脱...这些病态的想法
There are places where you can get help... for these morbid thoughts.
你是指精神病院?
An asylum, you mean?
你到底为了什么会杀害保姆?
Why on earth would you kill Nanny?
为什么?
Why?
你说当时在那儿是什么意思?
What do you mean you were there?
她的手腕已被割开
Her wrists were cut open.
我手里握着一把刀
I had a knife in my hand.
你做了些什么?
So what are you going to do?
我想要帮你
I want to help you.
噢 别管我了
Oh, please let me.
我对于自己犯下的所有过错万分抱歉
I'm so sorry for all the mistakes I've made.
我不需要你的帮助!
I don't need your help!
- 我不要任何人的帮助! - 诺尔玛
- I don't need anybody's help! - Norma.
大卫! 你在这儿干什么?
David! What are you doing here?
我来看你
I came to see you.
我觉得你也许想出去散散步
I thought you might like to go for a walk.
你有什么麻烦吗?
What's troubling you?
我觉得我快疯了
I think I'm losing my mind.
你对我可以畅所欲言 诺尔玛
You can tell me anything, Norma.
您好 我能为您效劳吗?
Yes? Can I help you?
是的 我是阿里阿德涅・奥利弗
Yes, I'm Ariadne Oliver.
那个...小说家?
The... The novelist?
抱歉 我们不买上门推销的东西
Sorry, we don't buy anything at the door.
前两天晚上我也来了克劳迪娅的舞会
I was at Claudia's party the other night.
您就是那个抱怨太吵的女士
You're the woman who complains about the noise.
只在你们跳舞的时候 我刚好住在你们楼下
Only when you're dancing. I live directly below, you see.
我想那也是为什么克劳迪娅邀请我的原因
I think that's why Claudia invited me.
我一直期待和诺尔玛说几句
I was hoping to have a word with Norma.
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克?
Norma Restarick?
总之 我和诺尔玛对现代小说谈得非常投契
So, you see, Norma and I were having a marvellous conversation about modern fiction
她还说她很喜欢我的一部作品
and she so sweetly said she'd like to read one of my poor efforts.
所以我答应送给她一本
So I promised to pop one round.
嗯... 然后您就来了
Mm... And here you are, popping it round.
嗯
Mm.
那么 你是第一个女孩
So, you're the first girl
你是第二个 你们是老朋友吗?
and you're the second. Are you old friends?
不是 我只是回应了克劳迪娅房屋合租的广告
No. I answered Claudia's advertisement in Rooms To Let.
诺尔玛也是?
And Norma?
为什么您对诺尔玛
Why are you so interested
如此感兴趣呢 奥利弗夫人?
in Norma, Mrs Oliver?
她好像被什么困扰着
She seemed troubled about something.
你很熟悉她?
Do you know her well?
诺尔玛的父亲是我的老板
Norma's father is my boss.
安德鲁・雷斯塔里克
Andrew Restarick.
啊 因此诺尔玛也就碰巧在这儿租下了一间房
Ah, so that's how Norma happened to take a room here.
我猜 他希望你能关照她
He wanted you to keep a kind eye on her, I suppose.
我想是吧
I suppose.
总之 我保证她会拿到书
Anyway, I'll make sure the book gets to her.
你也不知道她在哪儿?
So, you have no idea where she is?
诺尔玛常常上街
Norma walks the streets a lot.
她是个非常喜欢... 自我反省的姑娘
She's a very... introspective girl.
她有个她很喜欢的舅父 也许她去拜访他了
She has a great-uncle she's fond of. Perhaps she's gone to visit him.
不是的 诺尔玛已经不去十字树篱庄园了
No. Apparently, Norma doesn't go to Crosshedges any more.
她亲爱的舅父有了一位新的红粉知己
Her dear old doddery great-uncle has a new friend,
也就是说诺尔玛不再是他关心的对象了
which means that Norma is no longer the centre of attention.
- 就这些了? - 还有茶吗?
- Was that everything? - Is there any more tea?
"最后一个快乐的夏天"
"The last happy summer. "
- 噢! - 抱歉
- Oh! - Excusez-moi.
啊! 赫尔克里・波罗!
Ah! Hercule Poirot!
著名的侦探
The famous detective.
她说得对 您的确太老了
She was right. You are too old.
您是?
And you are?
- 贝克 大卫・贝克 - 啊
- Baker. David Baker. - Ah.
贝克先生 您和雷斯塔里克小姐很熟 是吗?
Monsieur Baker. You are an acquaintance of Mademoiselle Restarick, are you not?
可以这么说
You could say that.
我猜 您为她父亲工作?
You're working for her father, I suppose?
- 你不喜欢他? - 我从未见过他
- You do not like him? - I've never met him.
- 您有客人 先生 - 谢谢
- Your visitor, sir. - Merci.
你好 您就是那个比利时人?
Hello. Are you the chap from Belgium?
赫尔克里・波罗
Hercule Poirot.
是吗?
Are you?
罗德里克先生 时隔多年还能见到您
Sir Roderick, what a great pleasure it is
真是莫大的荣幸
to see you after all these years.
噢 是啊 的确
Oh, yes, indeed. Yes, indeed.
多久... 你说有多久了?
How long... How long would you say?
你信上写的不具体
Your letter wasn't specific.
啊
Ah.
我恐怕您已经不记得我了
I feared that you might have forgotten me.
不过用不着担心
But not to worry,
我只是碰巧来了十字树篱附近...
I merely happened to be in the vicinity of Crosshedges...
忘了你? 没有的事 亲爱的朋友 没有的事
Forgotten you? Not at all, dear chap, not at all.
- 坐吧 - 多谢
- Sit down. - Merci.
你说我们是在法国碰到的?
We met in France, you say?
对 在诺曼底
Oui, in Normandy.
就在大战期间 我们都决定了些什么呢?
During the Great War. What decisions we had to make, huh?
您本人 瑞斯上校... 阿伯克隆比将军
You yourself, Colonel Race... General Abercrombie.
还有你... 你就是那个法国小个子!
And you... you were the little Frenchie!
我是那个比利时小个子
I was the little Belgian.
噢 是的 当然了
Oh, yes, of course. Of course.
你还好吗 呃 波罗?
Those were the days, eh, Purot?
你见过老阿伯克隆比吗?
Do you ever see old Abercrombie?
时不时还见面 是的
Here and there, oui. From time to time.
告诉我 罗德里克先生
Tell me, Sir Roderick,
我注意到门厅的楼梯上
I could not help but notice in the hallway by the stairs,
- 有一副精美的画像 - 噢 没错 很多
- a portrait so fine. - Oh, yes, lots of those.
有一副画像中的女子非常美丽
This was a portrait of a woman so beautiful.
我觉得这幅画像的旁边应该还有一副
And it seemed to me that there must have been at one time a companion piece by its side.
曾经是有的 但不会再有了
Once upon a time. Not any more.
玛丽无法忍受看到它
Mary couldn't stand the sight of it.
玛丽是我最疼爱的侄女
Mary was my favourite niece.
她丈夫安德鲁...抛弃了她
Her husband Andrew... ran out on her.
已经二十年了
It must be 20 years now.
玛丽... 深受打击
Mary... took it badly.
毁了所有能让她想起他的东西
Destroyed everything of hers that reminded her of him.
包括那副该死的画像
Including that damn portrait.
如今他回来了 满心后悔
He's back now and full of regrets.
得知真相的时候悔之已晚
Hell is the truth learned too late.
请您告诉我 罗德里克先生
But tell me, Sir Roderick,
她丈夫 他还住在这儿吗?
the husband, does he live here still?
安德鲁? 不 没有 他住在伦敦
Andrew? No, no, he lives in London.
不过几天前他来看过我 待了整晚
Although he came to see me a couple of nights ago. Stayed all evening.
我秘书去了伦敦 他就来给我做伴
Keeping me company, he said, while my secretary was in London.
怎么都甩不掉这个该死的家伙
Couldn't get rid of the damn chap.
- 他们有孩子吗? - 有一个
- Did they have children? - One.
诺尔玛
Norma.
母亲呢?
And the mother?
玛丽・雷斯塔里克已去世多年
Mary Restarick has been dead for many years.
噢 索尼娅!
Oh, Sonia!
这位是我的秘书 索尼娅 也是我的眼睛
This is my secretary, Sonia. My eyes.
还有伴侣
And my companion.
久仰了 小姐 我是赫尔克里・波罗
Enchantè, mademoiselle. Hercule Poirot.
- 是的 我猜到了 我读过您的信 - 啊
- Yes, I guessed as much. I read your letter. - Ah.
罗德里克先生很容易疲倦
I'm afraid Sir Roderick tires easily.
他平时不接待客人
He doesn't normally see visitors.
抱歉
Je suis dèsolè.
那我就不耽误他的时间了
I will detain no longer of his time, huh?
我送您出去
I'll show you out.
- 不 不必烦劳 - 我坚持
- No, no, no, there is no need. - I insist.
雷斯塔里克夫人是个大美人吧 不是吗?
Madame Restarick was a woman most striking, no?
有画为证
Evidently.
请问她是怎么死的?
May I ask how did she die?
我听说她死得...很突然
I'm told she died... suddenly.
太悲惨了
How sad.
不过她女儿有来探望她的舅父 不是吗?
But her daughter comes to visit her grand-uncle, no?
诺尔玛再也不来了
Norma doesn't come here any more.
- 那是何故? - 我不清楚
- But for what reason? - I have no idea.
来这儿的人通常都是无事不登三宝殿
Nobody ever comes here unless they have good cause.
- 谢谢 - 先生
- Merci. - Sir.
怎么? 你在十字树篱有何发现?
Well? What did you find out at Crosshedges?
一无所获
Nothing.
真是无趣极了
How dreadfully dull.
根本不是
Not at all.
事实上波罗的一无所获
The fact that Poirot discovered nothing
意味着有很多事是被刻意隐瞒的
means that there is a great deal that is being concealed.
- 你有何发现? - 嗯...
- What did you find out? - Well...
... 第一个女孩告诉我
...the first girl told me
诺尔玛和她舅父闹翻了
Norma's had a falling-out with her great-uncle.
- 似乎是他有了新欢 - 啊 我明白了
- Something about a new friend he has. - Ah, that I can understand.
那么第二个女孩呢?
And the second girl?
她谈起诺尔玛的时候很热情
She spoke more warmly about Norma.
弗朗西丝・凯瑞 放荡不羁的那个
Frances Cary, the bohemian one.
是的
Oui.
连茶都不会泡
No idea how to make a cup of tea.
那姑娘是在哪儿长大的?
Where was the girl brought up?
当天您整晚都和雷斯塔里克小姐在一起?
And you were with Mademoiselle Restarick all of the evening?
- 在舞会上? - 是的
- At the party? - Oui.
呃... 吃冰淇淋的时候她回房了
Er... She went to her room when the ice cream came out.
哇噢! 谁想吃冰淇淋?
Hoorah! Who would like ice cream?
冰淇淋! 真是个好主意!
Ice cream! What a wonderful idea!
抱歉失陪
Excuse me.
我还留下了一份 再也找不到能说两句的人
I had a bowl then left. Didn't find anyone to talk to.
没人关心那部小说的命运
Nobody was interested in the fate of the novel.
连你说的那个艺术家也不感兴趣?
Not even the artist that you mentioned?
那个大卫・贝克?
This David Baker?
他怎么有空理会我
He was far too busy for me.
他整晚都在和弗朗西丝说话
He spent all evening talking to Frances.
我感觉他们不想让任何人听到他们的谈话
It struck me they didn't want to be overheard by anybody.
噢 还有一件事 克劳迪娅・瑞斯・霍兰德
Oh, one more thing. Claudia Reece-Holland,
她是诺尔玛父亲
she's secretary to Andrew Restarick,
安德鲁・雷斯塔里克的秘书
Norma's father.
看来我想见这位雷斯塔里克先生
Well, it seems I must make an appointment
必须要预约了 是不是?
to see this Monsieur Restarick, no?
- 能为您效劳吗? - 没什么了 夫人
- What can I do? - Nothing, madame.
- 没有? - 没有 真的没有
- Nothing? - No, nothing at all.
只是要当心 好吗?
Just be careful, huh?
只要有谋杀 什么事都有可能发生
Where there is murder, anything can happen.
谋杀? 谁被谋杀了?
Murder? Who's been murdered?
嗯 当然是施格兰姆保姆了
Well, Nanny Seagram, of course.
您认为她不是自杀的?
So you don't think she took her own life?
不不不
No, no, no.
我从没这么想过
Not for one second.
噢!
Oh!
我决定买点新鞋子
I decided to buy some new shoes.
- 你赞成吗? - 我喜欢腿
- Do you approve? - I like the leg.
- 这么说 他是你的老战友? - 谁?
- So he was an old war comrade of yours? - Who?
那个法国佬? 我从未见过他
The Frog? Never met him in my damn life.
你确定吗?
Are you sure about that?
他说他是不是和阿伯克隆比见面
He told me he sees old Abercrombie from time to time.
肯定是先做过调查的
Have to dig him up first.
我想他是来问有关诺尔玛和她妈妈的问题的
I think he came to ask questions about Norma and her mother.
嗯...一天里出现了两个爱管闲事的人
Hm... Two nosy parkers in one day.
你是说还有其他人来过?
You mean someone else has been here?
有个叫贝克还是什么的人也来打听过
Well, some arty type called Baker came snooping around,
问了些诺尔玛的问题
asking questions about Norma.
他在找...嗯...照片
And he was looking for er... for photographs.
好像是安德鲁委托他
Seems that Andrew's commissioned a portrait from him
画了一张肖像放在玛丽的旁边
to hang next to Mary's.
噢 也许这能让那个鬼魂消停一下
Oh, well. Perhaps it'll put that ghost to rest.
我喜欢全家福
I love family photographs.
额 对我再也没好处了
Well, no good to me any more.
我让他想要什么就自己拿
I let him take what he wanted.
他看起来是个无害的小伙子
He seemed a harmless enough chap.
噢 罗迪 你真是天真
Oh, Roddy, you're such an innocent.
你没想过他是觊觎诺尔玛的钱吗?
Doesn't it occur to you that he might be after Norma's money?
你知道的...自从我妻子死后
You know, er... since my wife died,
你的小说陪我度过了
I've spent many a lonely night
无数孤寂的夜晚 奥利弗太太
in your company, Mrs Oliver.
噢 上一本小说简直是天才之作
Ooh, that last one was a work of genius!
女士 不要往回看
Lady, Don't Fall Backwards.
噢 那很有趣 我发誓
Oh, that's funny. I could have swore
警察走的时候我把门锁了
I locked that when the police were done.
非常感谢 阿尔夫 你真好
Thank you so much, Alf, you're a dear.
我保证 我不会待很久的
I won't be long, I promise.
额 波罗也许愿意坐着什么也不做
He, Poirot, may be content to sit and do nothing,
而我 奥利弗 可不愿意
I, Oliver, am not.
谋杀
Murder.
鬼扯!
Fiddlesticks!
如果我小说里的女人...
If a woman... in one of my novels...
想要藏便条的话...
...wanted to hide a note...
会藏在哪里呢...
...where it would be found...
想藏遗书的话...
...wanted to hide a suicide note...
别人一定会找的地方...
...where someone was bound to look...
Where someone was bound to look.
别人一定会找的地方...
Where someone was bound to...
一个女人认为...
Where would a woman consider...
一个很明显...
...an obvious place...
要找的地方?
...to look?
"如果我死了 把这个交给警察"
"To be given to the police in the event of my death. "
是她 是第三个女孩
It's her. It's the third girl.
- 噢! - 我能帮你吗?
- Oh! - Can I help you?
请等一下
Un moment, s'il vous plait.
我在想...有没有可能
I wonder... if it might be possible
让我见见安德鲁・雷斯塔里克
for me to see a Monsieur Andrew Restarick.
赫尔克里・波罗
Hercule Poirot.
- 请坐 - 谢谢
- Take a seat. - Merci.
查票 请把票都拿出来
Ticket inspection. All tickets, please.
- 我要下车 - 我要检查你的票
- I need to get off. - I need to see your ticket.
- 我在跟踪一个人 - 你说什么 女士?
- I'm tailing someone. - Pardon, madam?
我说我在跟踪一个人!
I said I'm tailing someone!
没有票不行 不准下车
Not without a ticket, you're not.
是的 亲爱的
Yes, dear.
请给我一个甜面包和一杯咖啡
Bath bun and a cup of coffee, please.
什么?
Sorry?
请给我一个甜面包和一杯咖啡
Bath bun and a... cup of coffee, please.
赫尔克里・波罗先生
Monsieur Hercule Poirot.
雷斯塔里克先生
Monsieur Restarick.
你就是那个假装在战中认识罗迪叔叔
You're the chap who called on Uncle Roddy
而去拜访过他的人
pretending to know him from the war.
我想知道他是不是很客气
I wondered if he was just being polite.
当然 我知道 他不在意访客
And I am aware, of course, that he does not care for visitors.
当然 你不是这样
But not in your case, of course.
我很忙 波罗 说明你的来意
I'm a busy man, Poirot. State your business.
我是来和你谈谈你女儿拜访我的事
I am come to talk with you about the visit rendered to me by your daughter.
- 你见过诺尔玛? - 是的
- You've met Norma? - Yes, indeed.
她让我救她
She asked me to save her.
- 救她? 为什么? - 我也不知道
- Save her? From what? - Well, that I do not know.
你知道吗?
Do you?
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
恐怕我不能久留
I'm afraid I can't stay very long.
画室待会有人要来 画肖像
I've somebody coming to the studio. Portrait.
但我以为你说你有东西要给我看
Oh, but I thought you said you had something you were going to show me.
诺尔玛...我希望你停止担心
Norma... I want you to stop worrying
施格兰姆保姆的事
about what happened to Nanny Seagram.
你怎么会认为你会杀人呢?
What on earth makes you think you could kill somebody?
现在 我知道你是个很富有的年轻女人
Now, I know that you're a rather wealthy young woman,
- 也就是说你一定要小心 - 小心?
- which means you must be careful. - Careful?
- 先生? - 我要走了
- Sir? - I should go.
但我会再和你联系的 诺尔玛
But you'll hear from me again soon, Norma.
别相信任何人
Trust nobody.
连我也别相信
Not even me.
服务员! 服务员! 买单 快点
Waitress! Waitress! My bill, quickly.
我的女儿诺尔玛自从她妈妈死后
My daughter Norma has often needed psychiatric help
经常需要精神帮助
since her mother died.
她可能会...歇斯底里
She can get... hysterical,
感伤的...
melodramatic...
事实上 这都是我的错
The fact is, it's all my fault.
诺尔玛的妈妈...玛丽...
Norma's mother... Mary...
也觉得生活艰难
also found life difficult.
我懂了 真伤心
I see. How sad.
事实是...诺尔玛五岁的时候
The plain truth is, I left my wife...
我离开了我的妻子
when Norma was five.
我从未想过过我现在的生活
I never wanted the life you see me leading now.
我总是四处旅行
I was always a traveller.
脚痒
Itchy feet.
有一天 我决定...在南非开始新的生活
Well, one day, I decided... to start a new life in Southern Africa.
这是故事很普通 是吧?
That is a story most common, no?
但是玛丽无法面对这个打击
But Mary never got over it.
她变得越来越失常
She became more and more disturbed.
然后 有一天...
And then, one day...
在诺尔玛七岁的时候
...when Norma was seven,
在她的七岁生日那天
on her seventh birthday, in fact...
我妻子自杀了
...my wife killed herself.
见鬼!
Sapristi!
在她孩子的生日那天?
On the birthday of her child?
我觉得她没有打算自杀
I don't think she intended to kill herself.
我从保姆那里拿到的信上说得很清楚了
The letters I got from old Nanny made that pretty clear.
她打算...让人发现她
She intended... to be found.
然后...救她
And... saved.
告诉我 先生
Tell to me, monsieur,
你妻子的尸体是谁发现的?
who was it who actually discovered the body of your wife?
- 是诺尔玛 - 噢
- Norma did. - Oh.
试想一下那对她造成的影响
Imagine the effect that had on her.
这种事也许只会让成年人悲伤
Such an occurrence would be distressing to the mind of an adult,
但对小孩子来说...
but to that of a child...
先生 我想问问 是什么让你回英格兰的?
May I ask, monsieur, what it was that brought you back to England?
一年前 我哥哥死了 没有继承人
A year ago, my brother died, leaving no heirs.
我不得不结束旅行 回来接管生意
I had to return from my travels to take over the business.
所以 我就在这里了 只能在办公桌前卖命
So, here I am, tied to a desk.
这么说 你妻子葬礼之后
So, until last year you have not seen your daughter
你直到去年才见到你的女儿
since the funeral of your wife.
噢 不不 我妻子自杀的时候我出城了
Oh, no, no, I was up country when that happened.
那封信没有及时送到我手中
The letters never reached me in time.
所以你没有参加葬礼
So you did not attend the funeral.
- 没有 - 所以你和女儿团聚时
- No. - So the reunion with your daughter,
你们一定都很激动
when it happened, must have been full of emotion for you both.
你有孩子吗 波罗先生?
Do you have children, Mr Poirot?
没有
Mais non.
那你就无法想象那有多痛苦
Then you cannot possibly imagine how painful it was.
她看什么都不顺眼
And nothing's been right with her.
她很...生气
She's so full of... rage.
给波罗先生的紧急电话
An urgent call for Monsieur Poirot.
给我的?
For me?
- 我能接通吗? - 我先离开
- Shall I put it through? - I'll let you be private.
谢谢
Merci.
你好 是我 波罗 你是谁?
Hello. It is I, Poirot. Who speaks?
我是达芙妮 甜叶草茶屋的
It's Daphne, from The Merry Shamrock tearooms.
我想你可能打错电话了
I think perhaps you have the wrong number.
奥利弗太太说 我只能跟你说
Mrs Oliver said I was to speak only to you.
所以你的仆人乔治给了我这个号码
So your Mr George gave me this number.
我找到你了 波罗先生
I've tracked you down, Mr Poiry.
我要告诉你一些紧急的事
I'm to tell you something urgently.
告诉我什么?
Tell to me what?
第三个女孩... 现在处于...
"The third girl... is in danger...
孔雀的危险之中
...from the peacock. "
啊 孔雀
Ah. The peacock.
我要告诉你
And I was to tell you that
奥利弗太太现在正跟踪孔雀去他的画室
Mrs Oliver is now tailing the peacock to his studio.
我知道了 谢谢你
I understand. Thank you very much.
- 希望没什么大事 - 不不不不不
- Nothing serious, I hope. - No, no, no, no, no.
没什么大事
Nothing serious at all.
祝你今天过得愉快 先生 小姐
I wish you good day, monsieur, mademoiselle.
祝你今天过得愉快
Good day.
一切还顺利吗?
Is everything all right?
今晚和我共进晚餐
Have dinner with me tonight.
抱歉!
Excuse me!
老天 我真的不擅长这个
Goodness, I'm really not good at this.
- 你不擅长 是吗? - 噢 老天!
- You're not, are you? - Oh, goodness!
噢 你真让我吃惊! 我不知道你在那儿
Oh, you startled me! I had no idea you were there.
- 你在跟踪我 - 是的 恐怕是的
- You were following me. - Yes, I'm afraid I was.
我是写书的 我写的是侦探小说
You see, I write books. I write detective stories,
我刚刚想到 在现实生活中
and I just got it into my head to see what it would be like
真的跟踪一个人会是什么样的
to tail a real, live person in real, live life.
结果如何呢?
And how was it?
- 什么? - 跟踪一个真实的人
- What? - Tailing a real, live person.
噢...这比你想象的难多了
Oh... it's much harder than you think.
你也许会生气 但这完全没必要
You're probably frightfully angry, but there's really no need.
我会...
I'll toddle...
你当时也在聚会上 是吗?
You were at the party, weren't you?
喋喋不休地说现代小说的退化
Boring everybody stiff about the decline of the modern novel.
然后你也在咖啡厅
And then you were in the cafè, too.
你不想看看我要去哪里吗?
Well, don't you want to see where I was going?
你不想跟踪我...一路到底吗?
Don't you want to follow me... all the way to the end?
为什么不在那里转转...嗯?
Why not toddle up there... hm?
噢
Oh.
谢谢
Thank you.
进来吧 别不好意思
Come in. Don't be shy.
欢迎光临寒舍
Welcome to my humble abode.
噢! 这是你家吗?
Oh! Is this yours?
"要求堕胎的女孩"
Girl Demanding An Abortion.
- 你觉得怎么样? - 噢 亲爱的
- What do you think? - Oh, dear.
啊 在这儿 和以前一样锐利 我懂了
Ah, here already. Keen as ever, I see.
奥利弗太太 我们又见面了
Mrs Oliver, our paths cross again.
凯瑞小姐 对不起 我刚才没认出你
Miss Cary, I'm so sorry, I didn't recognise you at first,
你没有...没有...
without your... without any...
- 没有穿衣服? - 是的 全裸
- Without my clothes on? - Yes. Completely naked.
奥利弗太太很好心的
Mrs Oliver kindly came round to the apartment
把要给诺尔玛看的小说拿过来
to leave a novel for Norma to read.
是吗? 真好
Did she? That was kind.
真是一系列的巧合啊
What a series of coincidences.
我就在那里 在茶室里
And there I was, in the tearoom,
诺尔玛和大卫当时正在喝咖啡
when Norma and David were having a cup of coffee.
真的吗?
Were you really?
是的 事实上 我们都在那里
Yes, we were, as a matter of fact.
非同寻常的巧合
Extraordinary coincidence.
然后她想试试在现实生活中跟踪别人感觉如何
And then she decided to see what it would be like in real life to follow someone.
在伦敦的这么多人当中 她选择了我
And of all the people in London, she chose me.
额 不是...
Well, that's not quite how...
你喜欢你的这次生活调剂吗 奥利弗太太?
And how are you enjoying your slice of real life, Mrs Oliver?
你知道吗 这太有趣了
Do you know, it's absolutely fascinating.
好吧 我不想耽误你的时间
Well, I don't want to take up any more of your time.
我给你倒杯酒吧?
Can I offer you a drink?
谢谢 但我不喝酒
Thank you so much, but I don't drink.
噢 这位女士不喝酒 谁想得到啊?
Oh, the lady doesn't drink. Who'd have thought it?
你知道你在哪吗?
Do you know where you are?
知道 知道 我没事的
Yes, yes, I'll be fine.
噢 你的画真的很不错 让人印象深刻
Oh, your paintings are really very good. Terribly impressive draughtsmanship.
噢 标题我也很喜欢
Oh, and I like the title, too.
"要求堕胎的女孩"
Girl Demanding An Abortion.
公众会有热烈反响的
I think the public will respond.
右边还是左边?
Right or left?
什么 乔治?
Yes, George?
门房终于回电话了 先生
The concierge finally answered the telephone, sir.
今天稍早奥利弗太太离开布洛丁法院后
He hasn't seen Mrs Oliver since earlier today,
他就没见过她了
when she left Boradine Court.
他说她离开得很匆忙
She left in a great hurry, he says.
女士们
Les femmes.
这次应该是奥利弗女士了 乔治
That will be Madame Oliver now, George.
让她进来
Please to show her in.
快过来 波罗先生!
Come quickly, Monsieur Poirot!
你能救我吗? 求你了
Can you save me? Please.
求你了
Please.
- 波罗先生 - 早上好 女士
- Monsieur Poirot. - Good morning, mademoiselle.
- 我是在你的公寓吗? - 是的
- Am I in your apartment? - Oui, bien s?r.
我的医生只给你打了一点镇定剂
You know, my doctor gave to you only the little sedative,
你已经睡了十四个小时了
and you have slept for 14 hours.
- 有谁知道我在这? - 没有别人了
- Who knows I'm here? - No other person.
当然 除了我的医生和仆人乔治
Except, of course, for my doctor and mon valet, George.
你现在很安全 雷斯塔里克小姐
You are quite safe, Mademoiselle Restarick.
但是 你为什么觉得需要找我
But why did you feel the need to see me
谈施格兰姆女士的谋杀案?
about the murder of Mademoiselle Seagram?
这么说 你相信我? 其他人都不信
You believe me, then? Nobody else wants to.
我毫不怀疑她是被谋杀的
I have no doubt that she was murdered.
告诉我 女士
But tell to me, mademoiselle,
你为什么觉得是你杀了施格兰姆保姆?
why do you feel that it was you yourself who murdered Nanny Seagram?
这样的事以前在你身上也发生过吗?
Has anything of this nature ever happened to you before?
没有
No.
我现在想离开了
I'd like to leave now.
不不不 我请你留下来
No, no, no, I implore you to stay.
你是来寻求我的帮助的 我会帮你的
You came looking for my help and that is what I am giving to you.
我不想要你的帮助 我想离开
I don't want your help, I want to go.
离开去哪里呢?
But to go where?
女士 现在没有其他地方对你来说是安全的
Mademoiselle, there is no other place that is safe for you just now.
你和你的舅父关系密切吗 雷斯塔里克小姐?
Do you feel close to your great-uncle, Sir Roderick?
他以前常和我在一起
He used to have time for me,
但现在只和索尼娅在一起
but now he only has time for Sonia.
啊 从什么时候开始 她成了她的...
Ah. And how long has she been his...
...伴侣?
...companion?
她大概半年前来到十字树篱庄园
She arrived at Crosshedges about... six months ago.
我知道了
I see.
罗德里克先生是何时开始失明的?
When did Sir Roderick lose his sight?
他的视力一向不好
It was never good.
大概是十年前完全失明的
It failed completely about 10 years ago.
嗯
Hm.
打扰一下 先生
Excuse me, sir.
稍等 是乔治 我的仆人 也是大厨
Parfait! George, mon valet, is also the chef exceptionnel.
请坐 女士 接下来几天 我们需要你坚强点
Please eat, mademoiselle. We need you to be strong over the next few days.
- 为什么? - 你就吃吧 我们晚点再谈
- Why? - Just eat, and we will talk some more.
抓住孔雀
Catch the peacock.
如果我死了 告诉警察...
Tell the police in the event of my death...
你的头被打了 奥利弗太太
You've been hit on the head, Mrs Oliver.
- 你是谁? - 谁?
- Who are you? - Who?
- 谁? - 谁打了你的头?
- Who? - Who hit you on the head?
你是谁?
Who are you?
啊 我知道你是谁
Ah, I know who you are.
我不可能认错你的胡子
Couldn't mistake those moustaches anywhere.
你在这儿干什么? 我在哪里?
What are you doing here? Where am I?
我警告过你小心点的 女士
I warned you to be careful, chère madame.
哦...我的头好痛
Oh... my head aches.
你是被钝器打伤的 女士
You've been hit with a blunt instrument, madam.
你的手提袋里的东西被偷了
And the contents of your handbag have been stolen.
- 是孔雀偷的 - 她精神错乱了
- By the peacock. - She's delirious.
- 不 我没有 - 我保证 她一定是的
- No, I'm not. - I assure you, this is how she is.
告诉我 女士 你确实看到孔雀袭击你了吗?
Talk to me, madame. Did you actually see the peacock strike you?
这很重要
This is important.
她的记忆力可能有问题
She may have difficulty remembering things.
胡说1
Nonsense!
每件事我都记得很清楚
I remember everything vividly.
有一个"要求堕胎的女孩"
There was a Girl Demanding An Abortion.
那个女孩是谁?
Who was this girl?
虽然我看来不是那么回事
Though it didn't look like that to me.
是第二个女孩
It was the second girl.
有两个女孩要求堕胎?
There were two girls demanding abortions?
你确实看到孔雀袭击你了吗?
Did you actually see the peacock strike you?
不 我什么也没看到
No, I didn't see anything.
事情发生得太快了
It all flew by so quickly.
你还记得你的手提包里有什么吗?
Can you remember what was in your handbag?
我要睡觉了
I think I'll go to sleep now.
好的
Bon.
祝你今天愉快
I bid you good day.
是孔雀飞得很快吗?
Was it the... peacock that flew by quickly?
它们不是用跳的吗?
They jump, don't they?
- 你有访客 先生 - 嘘 乔治
- You have a visitor, sir. - Ssh, George.
罗德里克・霍斯菲尔德和他的...秘书
Sir Roderick Horsfield and his... secretary.
- 罗德里克先生? - 是的 先生
- Sir Roderick? - Indeed, sir.
噢 谢谢你 亲爱的
Oh, thank you, dearest.
很高兴见到你 罗德里克先生
A great pleasure to see you, Sir Roderick.
- 女士 - 波罗先生 很高兴再见到你
- Mademoiselle. - Monsieur Poirot. A delight to see you again.
真神奇 有个朋友给我打了电话
Wonderful thing, a telephone.
伦敦警察厅的高官 他告诉了我你的事
Rang a friend, top brass, Scotland Yard. He told me all about you.
很高兴你还记得我的名字
I am gratified that you even remembered my name.
请坐
Please to sit.
是索尼娅记得 小个子 大胡子
Sonia remembered it. Little chap, big moustache.
很显然 你是我们的第一大侦探
Apparently, you're our number one sleuth.
我在我的行业还不算失败
I have not been entirely unsuccessful in my profession.
就是这么回事 我有工作给你
That's the ticket. Got a job for you.
但我恐怕 我现在的时间都占满了
But I regret that my time, it is fully occupied at the present.
照顾诺尔玛 是吗?
Looking after Norma, aren't you?
我可不记得我这么说过
Ah, I do not remember saying that.
你问过和她有关的问题
You asked questions about her.
看吧 你骗不了索尼娅
You can't fool Sonia, you see.
是的
No, indeed.
不管怎样 我认为你不能解决诺尔玛的问题
Anyway, don't think you can solve the Norma problem.
你不能 没人能
You can't. No-one can.
可怜的孩子 一生的精神都不太正常
Poor girl's had a screw loose all her life.
但是诺尔玛会没事的 只要她能守住她的钱
But Norma will be fine, as long as she can hold onto her money.
她为什么会守不住呢?
Why should she not hold onto it?
因为有一个叫做大卫・贝克的小混蛋
Because there's a nasty little blighter called David Baker.
在帆布上做画
Daubs canvases.
索尼娅和我觉得他就是冲着钱来的
Sonia and I think he's after the money.
我希望你尽量多的帮我找出他的消息
I want you to find out as much as you can about him.
- 我会付你一大笔钱 - 我愿意试试
- I'll pay you handsomely. - I will try.
作为回报 也许你能帮我
And, in return, perhaps you might help me.
A J 巴特斯比这个名字有什么意思?
What does it mean to you the name A J Battersby?
你为什么...会问起她?
Why do you... ask about her?
她是女的 然后呢?
She is a woman, then?
啊 是的 她确实是个女人
Oh, yes. Yes, she's a woman, all right.
诺尔玛还小时 请她当了几个月家庭教师
She taught Norma privately for a few months, when she was a little girl.
她经营自己的学校 之后
Ran her own school. After that,
诺尔玛母亲过世后 我们送她去那里了
we sent Norma there after her mother died.
她不能待在十字树篱庄园了 你明白的
She couldn't stay at Crosshedges, you see.
啊 是的 我明白了 谢谢
Ah, yes, I see. Merci.
哦! 哈!
Oh! Ha!
对了 呃... 这周末我们有个小家庭派对
Yes, um... we're having a little house party this weekend.
- 也许你乐意来 - 我深感荣幸
- Perhaps you'd like to come. - I would be most honoured.
- 呃...你有女伴吗? - 没有
- Um... Do you have a woman in tow? - Non.
- 好吧 反正要带一个 - 啊
- Well, bring her along anyway. - Ah.
我能相信你吧 波罗
Can I rely on you, Purot?
是的 当然 罗德里克先生
Yes, of course, Sir Roderick.
- 再会 小姐 - 先生
- Au revoir. Mademoiselle. - Monsieur.
拜拜 先生 谢谢你
Goodbye, sir. Thank you.
你对这位年轻小姐有什么看法 乔治?
What is your opinion of that young lady, George?
呃 先生 如果让我说的话 我觉得他很爱她
Well, sir, if you'll allow me, I would reply that he'd got it badly.
很爱她 如果可以这么说的话 先生
Very badly, if I may say so, sir.
当然 像他这个年纪的先生 这很常见
It's not unusual, of course, in gentlemen of that age.
是的 乔治 那这位年轻小姐呢?
Yes, George, but what of the young lady?
啊 好吧 先生 她很特别
Oh, well, sir, she's quite a definite type.
我没法具体说出是什么
There's never anything you could put your finger on,
但...他们知道自己在干什么
but... they know what they're doing, I'd say.
嗯
Mm.
- 啊 去邦德街 - 好的 先生
- Ah. Bond Street. - Right, sir.
呃? 对此你怎么看?
Well? What do you make of that?
这个法国佬没有他自己想象的那么聪明!
The little Frog's not nearly as brainy as he thinks!
但是 只要他能帮我们
However, if he can help me
阻止那个...画匠就行了
stop that er... canvas dauber in his tracks, all well and good.
谁是我的小机灵 机灵鬼?
Who's my clever, clever man?
现在 我们今天的任务结束了吧?
Now, shall we conclude the day's business?
我最近和你父亲谈过
I spoke with your father recently.
- 你为他工作 这... - 不 不
- You're working for him, is that... - No, no.
我只是想见见他而已
I wanted to meet him merely.
他告诉我说
He told to me that
是他请求克劳迪娅・瑞斯・霍兰德小姐
he asked Mademoiselle Claudia Reece-Holland
让你成为第三个租客的
for you to be the third girl.
他不需要问 因为那套公寓是公司的
He didn't have to ask. The company owns the apartment.
啊
Ah.
保姆的公寓也是 当然
And Nanny's, of course.
你和瑞斯・霍兰德小姐是朋友吗?
And you and Mademoiselle Reece-Holland have become friends?
我没有朋友
I have no friends.
我曾以为我有大卫
I thought I had David.
贝克先生?
Monsieur Baker?
你很爱他 对吧?
You have fallen very much in love with him, no?
我只是犯傻而已
I was just being silly.
我真是太天真了 居然会相信他
It was naive of me to confide in him.
诺尔玛 你确实是个很可爱的女孩
You know, Norma, you really are a lovely girl.
特别是你笑的时候
Especially when you smile.
我现在是不是该心怀感动?
Is my heart supposed to melt now?
他一定认为我是个很容易得手的女孩
He must have thought me an easy catch.
当我去他的画室时 才意识到我有多么蠢
I only realised what a fool I'd been when I went to his studio.
诺尔玛! 不是你想的那样
Norma! This isn't what you think.
小姐
Mademoiselle,
你父亲告诉我 你母亲是自杀的
your father told to me about the day your mother died and... that she killed herself.
她的死对你的影响很大
And that the tragic nature of her death has marked you deeply.
我想 女士...
I beg of you, mademoiselle...
...你是否能确切的告诉我
...can you tell to me exactly
那天的事你还记得多少?
what you remember about that day so terrible?
我们已经迟了 诺尔玛
We're late already, Norma.
你妈说得很迫切 很严肃...
She was so very insistent. Your mummy said, very strictly...
求你啦! 求求你啦! 只要一个冰激凌!
Please, please, please! Just one ice cream!
妈妈不会介意的 今天是我生日
Mummy won't mind. It's my birthday.
她让我们马上回去准备派对
She wants us to return promptly to be ready for the party.
妈妈! 妈妈! 妈妈!
Mummy! Mummy! Mummy!
妈妈! 看我给你带什么了!
Mummy! Look what I got you!
你能救救我吗?
Can you save me?
但我没能救她!
But I couldn't save her!
你今天怎么样 小姐? 你什么都没吃
How are you today, mademoiselle? You have not eaten.
你很热情 波罗先生 但我得离开了
You have been very hospitable, Monsieur Poirot, but I should leave.
但你现在离开 能去哪里呢?
But if you left now, where would you go?
去十字树篱庄园 也许?
To Crosshedges, perhaps?
是的 那里有我所有快乐的记忆
Yes. All those happy memories.
当然有快乐的时光
Surely there were some happy times?
小女孩脸上带着微笑的时光?
Times when there was a smile on the face of that little girl?
杀害母亲的小女孩
The little girl who killed her own mother.
不 小姐 你母亲是自杀的
Non, mademoiselle, your mother killed herself.
我本可以救她的
I could have saved her.
迟到是我的错
It was my fault for being late.
没人会原谅我
Nobody ever forgave me.
这就是你想从施格兰姆保姆那里
Is that what you wanted
得到的吗? 原谅?
from Nanny Seagram? Forgiveness?
你上次见到施格兰姆保姆是什么时候?
When was the last time that you saw Nanny Seagram?
她死的那天晚上
On the night she died.
克劳迪娅说她留了个口信给我 要我去找她
Claudia said she left a message to go and see her.
啊 天呐 诺尔玛
Oh, God, Norma,
我给全忘了 施格兰姆小姐
I completely forgot. Miss Seagram.
她下午来找你了 她说想和你谈谈你母亲的事
She popped up to see you this afternoon. She said she wanted to talk about your mother.
我母亲?
Talk about my mother?
你记得发生什么了吗? 她给你开门了吗?
And can you remember exactly what happened? Did she open to you the door?
我记不得了
I can't remember.
不 她没有应门铃 但门是开着的
No, she didn't answer the bell, but the door was open.
你发现什么了?
And what did you find?
我手上有一把刀
I had a knife in my hand.
不
Non.
你习惯性带刀吗?
Do you habitually carry a knife?
它曾在我的抽屉里
It was in my drawer.
我一打开抽屉 刀就在那里
I opened it, and there it was, just lying there.
你记得自己放过刀吗?
Do you remember putting it there?
没有
No.
那你带着刀了吗?
So did you take the knife with you?
呃 我...
Well, I...
我肯定是这样做了 因为后来刀不在那里了
I must have done. It wasn't there later.
小姐 你能告诉我 进入施格兰姆小姐房间后
Mademoiselle, can you tell to me exactly what you found
你发现了什么吗?
when entering the apartment of Mademoiselle Seagram?
她死了 不是吗? 而我拿着一把刀
She's dead, isn't she? And I had a knife.
打扰一下 先生
Excuse me, sir.
不 乔治 请不要在这一刻打扰我们!
No, George, please, not just at this moment!
纳尔森警长来了 先生
Inspector Nelson is here, sir.
- 还有奥利弗夫人. - 警察?
- And Mrs Oliver. - The police?
很好 我要告诉他们 我要自首
Good. I want to talk to them. I want to confess.
不 不 不!
No, no, no!
不 请不要这样做 小姐 请你 等我一下
No, please, I beg of you, mademoiselle. Wait for me. Please.
我们稍后再谈
We will talk more of this.
你只需要相信我
Only trust me.
啊! 奥利弗夫人!
Ah! Madame Oliver!
警长 你康复了
Inspector. You are recovered, I see.
完全康复了 谢谢你
Fully, thank you.
- 我记忆也恢复了 - 啊!
- And my memory has returned. - Ah!
- 那封信 - 信?
- The letter. - The letter?
施格兰姆小姐的遗书
Miss Seagram's suicide note.
我在她的镜子后面发现的
I found it behind the mirror in her flat.
"如果我死了 请交给警察 "
"To be given to the police in the event of my death. "
不 不 这不可能
No, no. Pardon. That cannot be.
你的意思是她在信中说要自杀吗?
Are you saying that in this letter she announced her suicide?
我还没来得及看就被偷走了
I didn't have time to read it before it was stolen from my handbag.
那你怎么知道是遗书呢?
So how could you know it was a note of suicide?
- 还能是什么呢? - 还有其他什么吗?
- What else could it have been? - What else indeed?
你总是把事情弄得很复杂! 我又头疼了
You always want to make everything so difficult! I'm getting a headache.
警长 你带了我要的消息吗?
Inspector, have you brought to me the information that I requested?
你想要的都在这儿了
You'll find everything you wanted in here.
尽管不知道它还有什么用
Though what it matters now, I couldn't guess.
警长 发生什么了?
Inspector, something has happened?
- 看起来好像不是自杀 波罗 - 啊
- It seems it wasn't suicide after all, Poirot. - Ah.
验尸报告说施格兰姆小姐是死于窒息
Results of the post-mortem indicate that Miss Seagram died of asphyxiation.
她的手腕是死后才被割开的
Her wrists were cut after she'd stopped breathing.
该死!
Sapristi!
还有 诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克的室友
What's more, Norma Restarick's flatmate,
克劳迪娅・瑞斯・霍兰德
Claudia Reece-Holland,
前几天找过我
visited me a couple of days ago,
她说诺尔玛对她父亲都坦白了
and she told me Norma had made a clean breast of the business to her father.
- 啊 - 她还说他相信诺尔玛
- Ah. - She also said that he believed
也向你坦白罪行了 波罗
the girl had made the same confession to you, Poirot.
纯属好奇 呃? 你好像有什么隐瞒我
Just curiosity, eh? Seems you've been deceiving me.
不好意思 但请先等我一下
Je suis dèsolè. But do indulge me, if you please, for one moment.
你是否还记得雷斯塔里克先生的秘书
Can you remember exactly when it was
是什么时候说他女儿是凶手吗?
the secretary to Monsieur Restarick denounced his daughter as a murderess?
两天前
It was two days ago.
两天前? 正是我遭攻击的那天
Two days? That was when I was attacked.
你知道诺尔玛现在在哪里吗 波罗?
Do you have any idea where this girl is, Poirot?
我不能让你进去!
I cannot allow you in there!
你不要拦我! 我在这里
You can't stop me! I'm here.
我就是诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克
I'm Norma Restarick.
我杀了施格兰姆保姆
I killed Nanny Seagram.
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克 我现在以谋杀罪逮捕你
Norma Restarick, I am arresting you on a charge of murder.
谢谢你对我的帮助
Thank you for trying to help me.
对此我持保留态度 波罗
I take a very dim view of this, Poirot.
先生 我第一次见到这位小姐时
If you will, sir, the first time I clapped eyes on her
就觉得她很有爱心
I thought the young lady had birds in her attic.
非常感谢你 乔治
Thank you very much, George.
两杯咖啡 谢谢
Coffee for two, if you please.
现在 我有一大堆的事需要弄清楚
Now, then, there are a lot of things I'd like to know.
我没理解错的话
Am I to understand that
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克一直都和你呆在一起?
Norma Restarick has been with you all this time?
是的 不然还能在哪?
Oui, bien s?r. Where else?
你对于她被捕一点都不关心
You seem completely unconcerned at her arrest.
一点都不 只是不幸而已
Not at all. It is unfortunate.
她在我这待着会更舒服
She would have been much more comfortable remaining here, under my roof.
- 啊 - 那这又是什么?
- Ah. - And what is that?
这回答了我去约书亚・雷斯塔里克公司后
This answers a question that has been troubling me
一直困扰我的问题
ever since I made a visit to Joshua Restarick, Ltd.
到底是什么迷人的问题?
And what is this fascinating question?
呃 很简单
Well, simply this.
当我到那的时候
When I arrived there,
克劳迪娅・瑞斯・霍兰德小姐
Mademoiselle Claudia Reece-Holland was sitting at her desk,
正坐在她的桌子旁补妆
repairing her maquillage.
桌子上却没有任何信件或文件
And in front of her, there was no correspondence, no files.
在我拜访期间 电话只响了一次
And for the duration of my visit, the telephone, it sounded only once,
而且还是找我的
and that was for me
达芙妮小姐在甜叶草茶屋帮你打的
from Mademoiselle Daphne on your behalf from The Merry Shamrock tearooms.
所以 我请纳尔森警长帮我查了一下
And so, I asked the good Inspector Nelson to make the inquiry.
然后呢?
And?
约书亚・雷斯塔里克实际上
Joshua Restarick virtually
在两年前就因为生意变差
ceased trading as a business since two years,
停止交易业务了
after many years in decline.
哦 停!
Oh, do stop!
你又让我头痛了 你知道这对我不好
You're making my head ache again, and you know that's bad for me.
夫人 你见过那个女孩微笑吗?
Chère madame, have you ever seen the girl smile?
微笑?
Smile?
为什么这么问 见过
Why, yes.
当她看到大卫・贝克的时候
When she saw David Baker.
- 他呢? - 他什么?
- And did he? - Did he what?
对她微笑 我的意思是 他...
Smile at her. I mean, did he...
有没有看她的眼睛?
look her in the eyes?
他从未将视线从她身上转开过
He never took his eyes from hers.
- 这有什么关系吗? - 当然
- Does it matter? - But of course.
呃 我认为他很不可靠
Well, I think he's unreliable.
他在茶室时想对诺尔玛说什么 但没有成功
He was going to show Norma something at the tearooms, but that never materialised.
啊
Ah.
你还不觉得她也许不是你想的那样吗?
And has it still not occurred to you that she might be exactly what she appears to be?
我的意思是...她可能是精神病
I mean... criminally insane.
夫人 如果你想知道
Chère madame, if you want to know the real truth
关于诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐的真相
about Mademoiselle Norma Restarick,
你得和我一起去个地方
you will accompany me on a journey.
多亏了纳尔森警长的调查
Thanks to the inquiries of the good Inspector Nelson,
我们要去拜访一个她的老朋友
we will meet a very old friend of hers.
带四片阿司匹林应该不算多吧?
Would four aspirin be too much to take, I wonder?
您的来电让我很好奇 波罗先生
I was intrigued by your telephone call, Monsieur Poirot.
- 我听说过您的大名 当然 - 谢谢
- I have heard of you, of course. - Merci.
但在交谈之前我想先了解一些信息
But I should like a little more information before we talk.
好的
Yes, indeed.
嗯 好的 巴特斯比夫人
Eh bien, Madame Battersby,
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐拜访了我
this Mademoiselle Norma Restarick
她向我寻求帮助...
rendered to me a visit,
呃 她遇到了麻烦...
and she requested my assistance with... well, some difficulties she...
- 她被指控谋杀 - 谋杀?
- She's been charged with murder. - Murder?
呃...所以 我可不可以先问一下
Um...So firstly, may I ask
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐是这里的学生时
did you like Mademoiselle Norma Restarick
你喜欢她吗?
when she was here as a pupil?
- 所有的女孩子我都喜欢 - 当然
- I like all my girls. - Yes, of course.
那她是一个什么样的女孩呢?
But what sort of girl was she?
学习虽不是很好 但也还中规中矩
Not scholastically brilliant, but adequate.
那之前 你在十字树篱庄园教她时呢?
And before, when you taught her at Crosshedges?
呃 她很小 只有五岁
Well, she was very young, only five years old,
我在那里的工作时间很短
and my appointment was very brief.
出于什么原因呢?
For what reason?
我有机会开设自己的学校
I had an opportunity to set up my own school.
所以你离开雷斯塔里克家开办自己的学校?
So you left the family Restarick to set up this school?
- 是的 - 这可是冒了很大的险
- Yes. - That was an undertaking most audacious.
开始收支很难平衡 但 呃...
It wasn't easy to make ends meet at first, but um...
学校很快就盈利了
the school soon started to pay for itself.
可否告诉我 雷斯塔里克小姐喜欢笑吗?
Bon. And tell to me, did Mademoiselle Restarick ever smile?
什么?
I beg your pardon?
他的意思是 她是不是有点神经质
I think he means did she seem a little neurotic?
我想你应该知道 波罗先生
I think you're aware, Monsieur Poirot,
诺尔玛接受过很多次心理治疗
that Norma's received psychiatric assistance on more than one occasion,
包括她在这里的时候
including whilst she was here.
考虑到她的家庭情况 这也不足为奇
Which is hardly surprising, given her home circumstances.
她极度依恋的父亲
Her father, to whom she'd been extremely attached,
突然离家 呃...
left home suddenly and um...
呃 她母亲...没处理好这件事
well, her mother... didn't cope with that very well, I think.
还有她自杀的悲剧
And the tragedy of her suicide.
不 既然你提起这些
No, since you mention it,
我还真不记得她在母亲死后笑过
I can't recall Norma ever smiling after the death.
她的卧室成了她死去母亲的祭奠室
Her bedroom here became a shrine to her dead mother.
在我看来 她一生都在责备自己
It seems to me that she has been blaming herself all of her life.
大多孩子也会这样 不是吗?
As do most children, non?
确实如此
Indeed.
- 当他们不责备自己的父母时 - 是的
- When they're not blaming their parents. - Oui.
你有孩子吗 夫人?
Do you yourself have children, madame?
我没结过婚 波罗先生
I've never married, Monsieur Poirot.
哦 对不起... 小姐
Oh, je suis dèsolè... mademoiselle.
你说她把自己的卧室当母亲的祭奠室
You say that she kept her room as a shrine to her mother,
但你也说她极度依恋父亲
but you also say that she was extremely attached to her father.
有对父亲的祭奠室吗?
So there was no shrine to him?
有 在她心中
In her heart, yes.
她一直相信他会回来
She never gave up hope that he would return.
或者会有一封让她去父亲那里的信
Or that a letter would arrive asking her to go out and join him.
但都没有
It never did.
在她心里 是的
In her heart, oui.
但现实中 她房间里有没有呢?
But in reality, in her rooms?
根本没有他父亲的照片
There wasn't a single photograph of her father,
如果你是想知道这个的话
if that's what you mean.
他离开后 她妈妈毁了所有的照片
Her mother destroyed every single one she could find after he left.
事实上 说到母亲
Really, when it comes to the mother,
不能不问自己 在那个屋子里的...
one has to ask oneself, in that house...
...那孩子是谁?
...who was the child?
的确 那孩子到底是谁 嗯哼?
Vraiment. Who was the child indeed, huh?
而你也没法拿出一张她爸爸的照片是吗?
And you could not provide her with a photograph of her father?
什么 我?
What, me?
我是说 你有没有全家福
From the photographs you took of the family, I mean.
哦 明白了 当然 不 不 我没有
Oh, I see. Of course. No. No, I couldn't.
你觉得 我们是不是结束了?
Are we done, do you think?
是的
Oui.
我读过你所有的小说 奥利弗女士
I have all of your novels, Mrs Oliver.
不知道您能不能在我的书上签个名
And I wonder if you would be so very kind as to sign my copies.
我会感到十分荣幸的
I really would be so grateful.
可以 当然可以
Yes, of course.
- 有笔吗? - 有
- Do you have a pen? - Yes.
- 谢谢 真是太高兴了 - 我的荣幸
- Thank you, this is thrilling. - Pleasure.
从记录上看 诺尔玛马上就要过25岁生日了
I see from my records that Norma's about to reach her 25th birthday.
鉴于她拥有的财富 她很吸引某些人
She is quite a catch for somebody, given her wealth.
玛丽・雷斯塔里克是一个富有的继承人
Mary Restarick was a wealthy heiress,
而她把一切都留给了诺尔玛
and she left it all to Norma.
- 她多有钱? - 她死的时候
- How wealthy was she? - At the time of her death,
玛丽・雷斯塔里克差不多有七八万英镑
Mary Restarick's fortune was estimated at seven or eight hundred thousand pounds.
对了 当然 还有十字树篱庄园
And, of course, there's Crosshedges house, too.
那屋子不是属于罗德里克先生吗?
The house does not belong to Sir Roderick?
哦 当然不是
Oh, no.
他只是沾诺尔玛的光才住在这里
He lives there by the grace of Norma.
如果诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐意外死亡了
So if, by chance,
会怎样呢?
Mademoiselle Norma Restarick was to die?
好吧 一半的钱会给她的直系亲属
Well, half the money would go to her next of kin,
也就是她父亲 除非她结婚了
her father. Unless she were to marry.
为什么只有一半呢?
But why only half?
玛丽・雷斯塔里克十分爱十字树篱庄园
Mary Restarick loved Crosshedges.
她将另一半的钱留下来作为维护房子的钱
She ensured that half the family money would always go back to the guardian of the estate.
那么如果诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐不结婚的话
So if Mademoiselle Norma Restarick was not to marry,
钱会给谁?
that would be?
给她最爱的舅父 罗德里克先生
Her favourite uncle. Old Sir Roderick.
谢谢
Merci.
你告诉我的索尼娅...
This Sonia woman you told me about...
她显然希望罗德里克先生能够
she's obviously hoping old Roderick will
得到诺尔玛妈妈的钱
come into Norma's mother's money.
你不是说 罗德里克先生
Didn't you tell me Sir Roderick
让你干掉大卫・贝克先生吗?
asked you to flush out David Baker?
- 在我看来... - 我听见了 女士
- I said it seems to me... - I heard you, madame.
我在思考 这是我的习惯
I am thinking. It is my custom.
哦 就这样? 怎么样?
Oh, is that all? What about?
告诉我 女士
Tell to me, madame,
当你进入施格兰姆保姆的房间时...
when you entered the apartment of Nanny Seagram...
不顾我特意给你的警告
against the advice that I gave to you most expressly,
但先暂时让我们忽略这一点...
but let us overlook that for now...
...你是怎么进去的?
...how did you gain the entry?
哦 是门房阿尔夫
Oh, Alf, the concierge.
他愿意为我做一切 他说他是我的头号粉丝
He'd do anything for me. He's my number one fan, he says.
很好 他放你进去的?
How gratifying. He let you in?
是的 但事实上 这是多余的
Yes, but in fact, he didn't need to.
- 因为门并没有上锁 - 我明白了
- The door had been left unlocked. - I see.
然后 你一进去就发现了那封信?
And, once inside, you just discovered the letter?
我没告诉你我是怎么发现信的?
And I didn't tell you how.
没有
Non.
真是太聪明了 我说的是我自己
It was terribly clever, although I say it myself.
我只是问我自己
I simply asked myself,
"一个女人会把那个藏在..."
"Where would a woman hide... "
是的 是的 是的 但是还发生了什么吗?
Yes, yes, yes. But did anything else happen?
好吧...
Well...
过了一会儿 我就觉得...
for a second, I had the feeling...
...公寓里还有其他人
...that someone was there in the apartment.
但是当然这只是我的想象
But of course I imagined it.
总之 我跟我自己说
Anyway, I said to myself,
"一个女人会把那个藏在..."
"Where would a woman hide... "
等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你确定那里没有其他人了吗?
Are you sure that there was there no other person?
- 这很重要吗? - 极其的重要 女士
- Does it really matter? - This is of the utmost importance, madame.
哦 你真让人火大
Oh, you really are the most maddening man.
我不能确定那儿还有没有其他人
I couldn't say for certain one way or the other whether someone else was there.
我冲了出去 去追那第三个女孩
I rushed out, chasing after the third girl.
啊 对
Ah, bon.
一切都清楚了
All is becoming clear.
啊! 明白了!
Ah! Gotcha!
- 罗德里克先生 - 哦 又是你
- Sir Roderick. - Oh, it's you again.
我带来了雷斯塔里克小姐的画像
I've brought Miss Restarick's portrait.
好吧 过来
Well, come here.
来吧
Come on.
近一点
Closer.
你知道吗 索尼娅...觉得你是个坏蛋
You know, Sonia... thinks you're a bad egg.
如果这指的是我和诺尔玛
If that refers to me and Norma,
我可以向你保证 我只在乎她的利益
I can assure you I have only her best interests at heart.
是的 我知道
Yes, I can see that now.
你完全不会有任何麻烦的
You're not going to be any trouble at all.
你是个好人!
You're a good egg!
女仆会送你出去
The maid'll see you out.
你能把东西留在这里
And you can leave that thing here.
啊 该死!
Oh, damn!
啊 我亲爱的阿尔夫!
Ah, my dear Alf!
这是波罗先生
This is Monsieur Poirot.
- 哦 波罗先生 - 先生
- Oh, Mr Parot! - Monsieur.
告诉我 你是她的粉丝吗?
Tell me, are you a fan?
是的 当然是
Oui, naturellement.
你读过她最新的小说吗?
Have you read her latest?
哦 是的 是的 我可以确定我有
Ah, oui, yes, I am almost sure that I have.
好吧 也许你可以帮我 我读过四次
Well, maybe you could help me. I've read it four times
而且对于这事儿是谁干的 我还是毫无头绪!
and I've still got no bleeding idea who dunnit!
- 哦 - 不 不 真是个天才!
- Oh. - No, no, it's genius!
让他们继续猜 额 奥利弗女士?
Keep them guessing, eh, Mrs O?
额... 阿尔夫先生 请告诉我
Er... Monsieur Alf, tell to me, if you please,
你了解施格兰姆小姐多少?
how well did you know Mademoiselle Seagram?
我曾送过杜松子酒给她
I used to deliver her gin for her.
根据纳尔森警长说的 她喝了很多的杜松子酒
According to Inspector Nelson, she drank a lot of gin.
我会说 喝得越来越多
I'll say. More and more.
从什么时候开始的?
And since when?
比如说 她喝酒是突然一下变多的吗?
For instance, did her liking for the drink increase suddenly?
- 是的 大约最近六个月 - 我知道了
- Yeah, for about the last six months. - I see.
你还为她做过什么?
And tell to me, what else did you do for her?
比如 你给她寄过信吗?
For instance, did you post her letters for her?
她很少收到或是寄信
She very rarely received or sent letters.
因此对她来说 信件是很难忘的
So for her, they were memorable perhaps.
你有没有偶然在她死前给她寄过信?
Did you, by chance, post a letter for her shortly before her death?
哦 是的 有的 就在前一天!
Oh, yes, I did. The day before!
那你有没有偶然注意到 这信是给谁的?
And did you notice, of course by chance, to whom the letter was addressed?
这很重要
This is most important.
- 好吧 我确实看到了 - 啊!
- Well, it did catch my eye. - Ah!
是给安德鲁...
It was for Mr Andrew...
雷斯塔里克 是吗?
Restarick, non?
- 对的 - 嗯
- Correct. - Mm.
她是不是还有很多的访客?
Did she receive many visitors?
好吧 那个可爱的女孩 诺尔玛
Well, that funny girl, Norma.
她以前常常来这里
She used to be up there quite a lot.
有时是她的父亲 雷斯塔里克先生
Sometimes her father, Mr Restarick.
啊 好的
Ah. Bon.
你有访客 先生
A visitor, sir.
啊...贝克先生
Ah... Monsieur Baker.
我正等你呢
I was expecting you.
谢谢 乔治
Merci, George.
我欠你一个解释
I owe you an explanation.
你没有欠我什么
You owe to me nothing.
我想让你看看这个
I'd like you to look at this.
我向你保证没有必要了
I assure you that there is no need.
我知道这是什么 我不需要看
I know what it is, and it is not I who needs to see it.
我想我们第一次在十字树篱庄园见面的那天
I believe you have had this in your possession
这东西就在你手里了
since we first met that day at Crosshedges.
你应该是准备在甜叶草茶屋
You could have shown it to Mademoiselle Restarick
把这个给雷斯塔里克小姐看的
at The Merry Shamrock tearooms,
但你没有
and yet you did not.
她看起来如此脆弱
She seemed so fragile.
我不知道她会有什么反应
I didn't know how she might react.
贝克先生 诺尔玛小姐不是她母亲!
Monsieur Baker, Mademoiselle Norma is not her mother!
诺尔玛
Norma.
如果我告诉你我爱你 你相信吗?
If I told you I was in love with you, would you believe me?
有时...我们看见的并不是真相
Sometimes... we see what isn't really there.
我和弗朗西丝之间什么都没有
Nothing happened between me and Frances.
我要给你看一些东西
I have to show you something.
小姐... 我希望你能相信我
Mademoiselle... I asked you to trust me.
可以吗?
Will you?
好的
Bon.
谢谢
Merci.
拉!
Pull!
看着 我闭着眼睛都能做到
Watch this. I'll do it blind.
拉!
Pull!
看那里
Look over there.
你还好吗 奥利弗女士?
How are you, Mrs Oliver?
哦! 弗朗西丝
Oh! Frances.
小姐
Mademoiselle.
我真心希望你已经康复
I do hope you've recovered.
哦 头被打了的事
Oh, from the bump on the head.
不 是看见我的裸体的震惊
No. From the shock of seeing me in the buff.
如果大厅里的画是未完成的
If the painting in the hall is anything to go by,
那么雷斯塔里克先生的第一任太太真是个美人
Mr Restarick's first wife was quite a looker.
当然 就像克劳迪娅提醒每个人的那样
Of course, that was all a long time ago,
这是很久以前的事情了
as Claudia keeps reminding everyone.
也许他另娶了一个妻子...
Perhaps he'll gain a wife...
就在他失去一个女儿的时候
just as he loses a daughter.
来一杯吗 先生? 女士?
Drink, sir? Madam?
安德鲁
Andrew.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我说 你是谁?
I said, who are you?
我是你父亲 诺尔玛
I'm your father, Norma.
她在这里做什么?
What's she doing here?
诺尔玛 你还好吗?
Norma, are you all right?
但我以为... 我们都以为...
But I thought... we all thought...
你们以为什么?
What did you think?
亲爱的诺尔玛 不要紧张
Darling Norma, please try not to get overwrought.
好吧 好吧! 你是来搞破坏的 是吧?
Well, well! Come to spoil another party, have you?
警察们在干什么 就这样放了她?
What are the police playing at, letting her out?
- 住嘴! - 噢!
- Shut up! - Ow!
- 诺尔玛! - 诺尔玛!
- Norma! - Norma!
很抱歉 我只是...我只是不明白!
I'm sorry, I just... I just don't understand!
警察放了我 爸爸 我自由了
The police let me go, Daddy. I'm free.
真是...真是太棒了
That's... That's wonderful.
罗迪叔叔如果看见你在这儿会高兴的
Uncle Roddy will be so happy that you're here.
亲爱的女孩 你让我想起了你妈妈
Darling girl, you remind me so much of your mother.
如果她能在这儿看见你
If only she were here to see you now.
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 哦 我的天呐 她疯了! - 诺尔玛!
- Oh, my God, she's insane! - Norma!
- 她还好吗? - 当然
- Is she all right? - Parfaitement.
她正在处理萦绕在她心头的记忆
She is dealing with the memories that haunt her.
她能扛过去吗?
But is she strong enough to go through this?
游戏该结束了
Let the game be played out.
诺尔玛! 这只会让事情越来越糟
Norma! This is only making things worse for yourself.
你在浪费你的时间 弗朗西丝
You're wasting your time, Frances.
你疯了 是吗?
You really are insane, aren't you?
我不想和你说话! 我不想和任何人说话!
I don't want to talk to you! I don't want to talk to anyone any more!
- 干杯!  - 大卫 亲爱的 干杯!
- Cheers! - David, darling, cheers!
我能...我能打扰一下吗?
May I... May I interrupt?
请安静一下! 罗德里克先生有话要说!
Quieten down, please! Sir Roderick wishes to speak!
- 哦 谢谢
- Oh. Thank you.
第一 我感谢你们在这特殊的日子前来
First, I'd like to thank you all for coming here on this special day.
特别是诺尔玛再次回到了我们身边
Especially Norma, who is back with us again.
而现在 我邀请你们所有人来的原因
And now, the reason I invited you all here.
会让你们中的一些人吃惊...而一些人不会
Something that will surprise some of you and... not others.
两周前 我向我的秘书
Two weeks ago, I asked my secretary,
索尼娅・班森小姐求了婚
Miss Sonia Benson, to be my wife.
我诧异的发现...她接受了!
I was astonished to find that... she accepted!
两天前 她还在担心
Two days ago, worried perhaps that
她的新郎可能会倒下去...
her bridegroom might keel over...
索尼娅说服了一位非常乐意的骑士
Sonia persuaded a very willing knight of the realm
陪她去了登记处 我们在那里结婚了
to accompany her to a registry office, where we were married.
那么 举起你们的酒杯...
So, raise your glasses...
举起你们的酒杯吧  女士们先生们
raise your glasses, ladies and gentlemen.
为了索尼娅・霍斯菲尔德女士干杯
The toast is Lady Sonia Horsfield.
为了索尼娅・霍斯菲尔德女士
To Lady Sonia Horsfield.
你高兴吗 索尼娅? 你现在高兴了吗 嗯?
Are you happy, Sonia? Happy now, are you?
十分高兴
Very happy.
你呢? 你让我成为这世上最幸福的男人
Are you? Because you've made me the happiest man in the world.
该死...我们太迟了
Sacrè... We are too late.
雷斯塔里克先生 请先让我处理这件事
Monsieur Restarick, please, allow me to deal with this immediately.
我们怎么会没预见到这种事?
How could we not see this coming?
请你节哀 罗德里克先生
I am so sorry for your loss, Sir Roderick.
这真是最大的悲剧
This is indeed a tragedy most terrible.
我还是不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
当然 除了一个人
Except, of course, for one person.
我说的是那个期盼
And I refer to the person who had hoped for
甚至是推动这次惨案发生的人
and encouraged this tragedy for a long time.
是谁想诺尔玛死?
Who could possibly wish Norma dead?
啊 是谁呢 嗯?
Ah. Who indeed, huh?
也许就是你自己 索尼娅女士
Perhaps you yourself, Lady Sonia.
从她母亲的遗产方面来说
In the terms of the legacy of her mother,
你的新丈夫能继承诺尔玛小姐一半的财产
your new husband inherits half a portion of the fortune of Mademoiselle Norma.
也许是克劳迪娅小姐
Or perhaps Mademoiselle Claudia,
你对她的蔑视相当明显
who despised her in a manner that was so obvious,
而且也可能和她的父亲结婚
and who had the hope of marrying her father,
他也能从他亡妻那里继承一半的财产
who also inherits a half share of the fortune of his late wife.
或者是弗朗西丝・凯瑞小姐?
Or Mademoiselle Frances Cary?
她疯狂的迷恋上了那个
Who had become so infatuated with the young man
深深爱着诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐的帅哥
who was so loved by Mademoiselle Norma Restarick,
大卫・贝克先生...
Monsieur David Baker...
而他爱上她的原因好像是他发现她很有钱
whose love for her seemed to increase the more he discovered how wealthy she was.
为了能够找到这个问题的答案
But in order to answer this question,
我们需要再问一个问题
it is necessary to ask another.
先让我们回到最开始
So let us go back to the very beginning.
谁希望施格兰姆保姆死?
Who wished to kill Nanny Seagram?
哦 求你了! 现在的时机和地点都不对!
Oh, please! This is not the time or place!
诺尔玛已经认罪了
Norma confessed to that.
我想这就是她为什么...
I think that's why she...
再说 这能有什么帮助呢?
And what is all this in aid of?
先生 我希望你能先让波罗先生说完
Sir, I'd ask you to allow Monsieur Poirot to speak.
谢谢 纳尔森警长
Merci, Inspector Nelson.
当诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐来找我时
When Mademoiselle Norma Restarick rendered to me the visit,
她说她好像杀了人 她求我...求我救她
she said that she might have committed a murder, and asked me to... save her.
我觉得这不可能是杀人犯说的话
I would suggest that those are the words not of a murderer
而是受害者说的话
but of a victim.
施格兰姆保姆是被谋杀的?
Was Nanny Seagram murdered?
还是像警察简单认为的那样...
Or was it, as the police seemed to assume, too easily...
...是自杀?
...the suicide?
我不确定
I could not be sure of the answer.
但是在照片后面的字...
But an inscription on the back of a photograph...
"十字树篱庄园 长基 1917年
"Crosshedges, Long Basing, 1917.
最后一个快乐的夏天
The last happy summer.
A J 巴特斯比"
A J Battersby. "
...这让我把这次的死亡
...caused me to suspect that the death
与诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐和施格兰姆保姆
was somehow connected with some trauma
身上的外伤联系在一起
in the lives of Mademoiselle Norma Restarick and the Nanny Seagram.
所以 我去了一趟十字树篱庄园
So, I made a visit to Crosshedges.
此行为我的调查带来了重要的发现
And I learned there something crucial to my investigation.
我在那里碰到了大卫・贝克先生
I made the acquaintance there of Monsieur David Baker.
为什么他在那?
Why was he there?
据罗德里克先生说 他是想要这家人的照片
Well, according to Sir Roderick, he wanted some photographs of the family
因为他打算画一幅
because he was about to execute a portrait
安德鲁・雷斯塔里克先生
of Monsieur Andrew Restarick
年轻时候的画像 是吗?
as a young man. Oui?
他很冷淡地对我说了句让我起疑的话
A man of whom he spoke to me with great cynicism and said, most revealingly...
我从没见过他
I've never met him.
这话真奇怪啊 你说是吗 先生?
That's a thing most strange to say, n'est-ce pas, monsieur?
我扯远了 让我们回到施格兰姆保姆
I digress. Let us return to Nanny Seagram,
一个上了年纪又有酒瘾的女人
a woman who was old, who was vulnerable, who had a problem with drink,
据看门人说
which, according to the concierge,
自从安德鲁・雷斯塔里克先生从南非回来后
increased since the arrival
酗酒就更严重了
from South Africa of Monsieur Andrew Restarick.
我想知道原因
I wondered why.
她依靠雷斯塔里克公司的资助来维持生计
She was dependent on the good will of the company Restarick for the roof over her head.
但她没必要担心
But she had no need to worry.
你最有理由感谢她 对吗 先生?
For you had reason most sound to be grateful to her, had you not, monsieur?
为她给这个家服侍了这么久 对的
For all her service to the family, yes.
是 也为了她帮你冒充一个已死的人
Oui. And also for helping you to impersonate a man who was dead.
一个已死的人?
A man who was dead?
纳尔森警长昨天查到的消息证实了我的怀疑
The inquiries of Inspector Nelson confirmed my suspicions yesterday.
今天 我收到南非来的电报
And today... I received a telegram from South Africa,
证实了安德鲁・雷斯塔里克先生
confirming the death of Monsieur Andrew Restarick
一年前已经去世
it is now since one year.
先生 今天诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐问你的
So, monsieur, as Mademoiselle Norma Restarick demanded of you today,
我 赫尔克里・波罗 也想问你
I, Hercule Poirot, also demand of you.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我叫罗伯特・奥威尔
My name... is Robert Orwell.
安德鲁・雷斯塔里克生前是我的好友
Andrew Restarick was my good friend.
死后亦是我的好友
None of this was ever meant to end in death.
你... 你是个骗子?
You... You are an impostor?
不 罗迪 不 坐下
No, Roddy, no. Sit down.
真正的安德鲁・雷斯塔里克
The real Andrew Restarick has not been seen
20年来从未来过英国
in England for 20 years.
被他抛弃的妻子
His wife, whom he abandoned...
毁掉了一切关于他相貌的物件
...had destroyed every image of him she possessed,
算是被她亲手杀死了
and was now dead by her own hand.
罗德里克先生 啊 他失明了
Sir Roderick, alas, had lost his sight,
而他的女儿诺尔玛
and his daughter, Mademoiselle Norma,
五岁以后再也没有见过他
had not seen him since she was five years of age.
只有一个人可以揭穿他的骗局
There was now only one person who could give away the game.
施格兰姆保姆
Nanny Seagram.
你威胁她 如果她敢揭穿你 你就会赶她走
Threatened with eviction if she attempted to expose you,
而且还用无限量的杜松子酒来贿赂她
and bribed with a supply, seemingly without end, of gin,
后来她同意了你的计划
she had fallen in with your plans.
现在你可以自由地接管公司
Now you were free to take over the business.
可以把它卖给最高出价人
Now you would sell it to the highest bidder.
- 你错了 波罗 - 恩?
- You're wrong, Poirot. - Hm?
这公司不值钱
The business was worthless.
但你离开南非之前并不知道
But you could not have known this before you left South Africa.
还能有什么原因让你来这儿?
Why else would you come here?
- 我没有杀害任何人 - 但你有动机杀人
- I never murdered anyone. - But you had the motive.
你害怕施格兰姆保姆会去揭穿你
Fearing that Nanny Seagram was about to expose you,
所以有必要让她永远沉默
is was necessary perhaps to silence her.
但当诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克认罪时
Ah, but when Mademoiselle Norma Restarick confessed to the murder,
你突然就意识到
you suddenly realised that,
作为安德鲁・雷斯塔里克先生
ah, as Sir Andrew Restarick,
你就是最近的血亲
you were next of kin.
你可以继承她母亲一半的财产
You would now inherit half the legacy of her mother.
所以你袖手旁观没有阻止她
So you stood by in silence and let her.
现在你离大富豪只有一步之遥
You were now within inches of becoming the millionaire.
甚至也可以说你是刽子手的刀
One might even say the length of the rope of... the hangman.
但现在 这些财产不会属于你了 先生
But now, this fortune will not go to you, monsieur,
不会属于一个被揭穿的骗子
an impostor who has been revealed,
钱会给罗德里克先生
but to Sir Roderick.
我的丈夫并不在乎那些
My husband doesn't care about that.
他只想诺尔玛能活过来
He just wants Norma back.
你这禽兽! 你怎么下得了手?
You monster! How can you do this?
等一等 警长
One second, Inspector.
最近有些新消息引起了我的注意
There has recently come to my attention some information that is new.
在座还有另一个人
There is one other person here
有权继承诺尔玛小姐的财产
who has the claim to the fortune of Mademoiselle Norma Restarick.
我在施格兰姆保姆的公寓发现的照片
The photograph that I discovered in the apartment of Nanny Seagram
被诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐的前家庭教师
was taken by the former tutor of Mademoiselle Norma Restarick -
一位叫A J 巴特斯比的女士拿走了
a Mademoiselle A J Battersby.
我去拜访了现在由她担任校长的学校
I paid a visit to her school where she is now the principal.
我发现了有一位女士谈及被抛弃的孩子
And I found there a woman full of emotion about a child who had been abandoned,
和一位遗弃母女俩的父亲时很激动
and a man who had deserted them both.
她一直坚信他会回来
She never gave up hope that he would return.
或者会有一封让她去父亲那里的信
Or that a letter would arrive asking her to go out and join him.
但都没有
It never did.
并且 这位女士用错误的时间误导了我
And a woman, moreover, who misled me about dates.
她说她辞去了诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克的
She told to me that
家庭教师的工作后
she had moved straight from her employment
立刻开始建立了自己的学校
as the tutor to Mademoiselle Norma Restarick into setting up her own establishment.
但是那时诺尔玛小姐才5岁
But that was when Mademoiselle Norma was five years of age,
现在已经过了20年了
and that is now since 20 years.
但是曼顿菲尔德学校只有十八年的历史
But Meadowfield School, it was only established it is now since 18 years.
那么这两年间她在做什么呢?
So what did she do in the two years in between?
为什么她这么短的时间就离职了呢?
And why had she left her employment after so brief a time?
现在 罗德里克先生
Now, I would like to ask you, Sir Roderick,
我想让你来证实我的怀疑
to confirm my suspicions.
为什么巴特斯比女士
The reason why Mademoiselle Battersby
这么突然地离开十字树篱庄园呢?
left Crosshedges so abruptly
因为她爱上了安德鲁・雷斯塔里克
was because she had fallen in love with Andrew Restarick
还怀了他的孩子
and conceived by him a child.
对吗?
Am I correct?
是的 波罗 你说的没错
Yes, Poirot, you are correct.
她突然离开 消失了两年
She left suddenly. Disappeared for two years.
这样啊
C'est sa.
她悄悄离开了
So she went away secretly.
生下了孩子 一个女孩
Bore the child. A girl.
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐同父异母的妹妹
The half-sister to Mademoiselle Norma Restarick.
是这样吗 凯瑞小姐?
Is that not so, Mademoiselle Cary?
或许我应该叫你...巴特斯比小姐?
Or should I call you... Mademoiselle Battersby?
我从小一直梦想有一天能找到我的姐姐
I grew up dreaming that one day I'd find my sister.
当我找到她时...简直就像是奇迹
When I found her... it was like a miracle.
我知道克劳迪娅在这个家族企业工作
I knew Claudia worked for the family firm,
我简直不敢相信诺尔玛也搬进来了
and I couldn't believe my luck when Norma moved in too.
我很想告诉她 她有一个妹妹
I longed to tell her she had a sister.
- 但她现在没机会知道了 - 嗯
- And now she'll never know. - Non.
讽刺的是 诺尔玛小姐死后
And the irony, with Mademoiselle Norma... gone...
你却有权继承她的财产
...you have a claim that is legal to her fortune after all.
是吗?
Does she?
但一切都无法让诺尔玛复活了 对吗?
But nothing can bring Norma back, can it?
嗯
Non.
一切都无法让诺尔玛小姐复活了
Nothing can bring back Mademoiselle Norma.
警员!
Constable!
诺尔玛!
Norma!
但你已经死了啊
But you're dead.
我看见你死了
I saw you dead.
你看见的是你想看见的
You saw what you wanted to see.
女士们先生们
Messieurs-dames,
波罗为你们揭秘真相的时刻到了
it is now the time for Poirot to unveil to you the truth.
在今晚雷斯塔里克小姐去浴室时
When Mademoiselle Restarick drew her bath this evening,
凯瑞小姐发现重现
Mademoiselle Cary saw this as the opportunity irresistible
她母亲自杀情形的机会来了
of replicating the circumstances of the suicide of her mother.
但我早已预见了这事并做了预防措施
But knowing this was going to happen, I took a precaution.
大卫・贝克先生发现你拿着枕头走进了浴室
You were observed by Monsieur David Baker entering the bathroom with a pillow.
为什么?
Why?
为了闷死她
In order to smother her.
太可笑了!
This is risible!
为什么我要这么对我姐姐呢?
Why would I ever do such a thing to my sister?
还有什么报复方法能比从抛弃你的父亲手中
What revenge more sweet could you have on a man who abandoned you
把婚生的姐姐的继承权夺来更好吗?
than to steal the inheritance of his daughter who was legitimate?
你同父异母的姐姐享有的财产
The inheritance of your half-sister that was so privileged,
被你继承了 真可恨
and by you, so hated!
当你母亲知道雷斯塔里克先生回英国后
When your mother learned that Monsieur Restarick had returned to this country,
她去找过他
she went to confront him.
但她发现那是个冒牌货
But she found there instead the impostor,
是罗伯特・奥威尔先生
Monsieur Robert Orwell.
最遗憾的是 她把这件事告诉了你
And, most regrettably, she shared this information with you.
而这正是你期盼已久的机会
And recognising this as the opportunity for which you had wished so long...
你 弗朗西丝・凯瑞小姐 瞒着你母亲
...you, Mademoiselle Frances Cary, unbeknown to your mother,
找到了这个冒牌货奥威尔先生
confronted the impostor, Monsieur Orwell,
坚决让他加入你可怕的计划
and insisted that he join in your plan so terrible.
你希望能以"自杀"的方式溺死她
You wished to steal
或者让她发疯
the inheritance of Mademoiselle Norma
以此来夺得她的遗产
by driving her to suicide or insanity.
为了让计划实现
And in order to achieve this end...
你让奥威尔先生把她安顿在
...you had Monsieur Orwell install her
施格兰姆保姆住的公寓里
in the building of apartments that also housed Nanny Seagram -
这个女人死在她眼前
a woman whose very presence would remind her of the guilt she felt
会让她想起母亲自杀给她带来的内疚
over the suicide of her mother.
你计算好了这将给她敏感的回忆带来的影响
You calculated the effect that this would have on a mind so fragile,
而你 作为心怀美梦的演员 你当然会扮演
and you, as the actress with aspirations, of course you would play the part
讨人喜欢的支持朋友的角色 对吗?
of the friend so loving and so supportive, huh?
可怜的诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐
Pauvre Mademoiselle Norma Restarick,
现在如此的脆弱
who was now so frail,
变成了你的猎物
had become your prey.
你! 当然 你一直在那儿陪她
You! Of course, you were always there for her...
诺尔玛 你要让我进来陪陪你吗?
Norma, would you like me to come and sit with you?
挑起那些痛苦的回忆!
...provoking memories that were painful!
谁要吃冰淇淋?
Who would like ice cream?
你甚至计划夺走想给她真爱和希望的
You even planned to steal away the young man who tried to give to her existence
年轻小伙子
real love and hope.
但这次挑战
But this campaign
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐心理的行动
against the psyche of Mademoiselle Norma Restarick
在谋杀施格兰姆保姆的事件上达到了高潮
reached its climax so inglorious in the murder of Nanny Seagram.
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克如你所愿地
It was no accident that
想起了她的母亲!
Mademoiselle Norma Restarick felt responsible for her mother!
这是你精心安排算计的!
You orchestrated this conviction with precision!
你的计划
Your plan...
主要靠两把...一模一样的刀
...depended on two knives that were... identical.
第一把 你放在她肯定能看到的房间的某处
The first knife, you left in her room where you knew she would look.
然后 派对之前
And then, before the party,
雷斯塔里克小姐去找施格兰姆保姆前
before Mademoiselle Restarick could reach her,
你残忍地杀害了无助的施格兰姆保姆
you sealed the fate so brutally... of Nanny Seagram, who was helpless.
然后在那里留下了第二把刀
And left behind there the second knife.
你一知道诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克发现了尸体
Once you had learned that Mademoiselle Norma Restarick had discovered the body,
就立刻藏起了诺尔玛小姐留在抽屉的第一把刀
simply you had to remove the first knife, that Mademoiselle Norma had left in her drawer.
而现在 她的记忆彻底混乱了
And now, with her mind in a state of total confusion,
诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐坚信自己犯下了罪行
Mademoiselle Norma Restarick was fully convinced that she had committed the act.
也许现在她就打算要自杀了
And she was headed now perhaps towards the suicide.
但当她认罪时 结果也是一样
But when she confessed to the murder, the result would be the same.
她会被处死
She would hang.
当她今早从监狱里释放时 你别无选择了
And when she was released from prison this morning, there was only one option open to you.
只有加快她的死期 但我
To hurry along her death. But I,
赫尔克里・波罗 答应过要救她!
Hercule Poirot, had promised to himself to save her!
对此我唯一能做的
And the only way I could do this...
就是在你之前...杀死她
...was to kill her before you could.
- 我根本没参与这些 波罗 - 骗子!
- I had no part in this, Poirot. - Liar!
在杀害施格兰姆保姆一案中 先生 你没参与
In the murder of Nanny Seagram, monsieur, non,
因为你有那晚不在场证明
for, en effet, you had provided for yourself an alibi that night.
但我想知道为什么有人会在谋杀当晚
But I did wonder why someone wanted to be somewhere else, in a manner so obvious,
特地出现在别处
on the night of the murder.
你在这里的那晚 你知道会发生什么?
That night you were here, you knew what was going to happen?
当然 怎么知道的?
Naturellement. How?
因为杀人犯是他的同谋
Because the killer was his accomplice,
弗朗西丝・凯瑞小姐!
Mademoiselle Frances Cary!
打断一下
Excuse me a moment.
你能解释下为什么他们中的一个要袭击我吗?
Can you explain why one of them decided it was necessary to attack me?
好吧 夫人
Ah, well... madame,
这都是因为施格兰姆保姆写的那封信
all this hinges on a letter that was written by Nanny Seagram.
她可以容忍奥威尔先生伪装成雷斯塔里克先生
She could endure the pretence that Monsieur Orwell was Monsieur Restarick,
却她发现这场邪恶的计划慢慢偏离了计划
but the sheer wickedness of this new conspiracy proved too much for her.
于是 她写了一封信给你 对吗 先生?
So, she wrote to you a letter, did she not, monsieur,
威胁说如果你不停止的话就要告发你
threatening to denounce you if you did not desist?
此外 为了保护自己不被你报复
And, in order to protect herself from your retribution,
她藏了一份那封信的复印件
she hid a copy of that letter to be read
以防她有任何意外
in the event of her death.
她告诉你 她已经这么做了
And told to you that she had done so.
所以现在 在你眼里 凯瑞小姐
So now, in your eyes, Mademoiselle Cary,
施格兰姆保姆必须得死
Nanny Seagram had to die.
必须拿回那封信
And that letter had to be retrieved.
但奥利弗夫人先你一步到那
But Madame Oliver had got there first.
奥威尔先生和克劳迪娅小姐不会看到
It could not have been Monsieur Orwell or Mademoiselle Claudia
看到奥利弗夫人拿到那封信
who had observed Madame Oliver retrieve that letter,
因为他们和我在一起
for they were with me.
不 小姐 是你看到了她
No, Mademoiselle, it was you yourself who observed her
然后打电话告诉奥威尔先生这事
and called Monsieur Orwell to inform him of this fact.
当达芙妮女士从甜叶草茶屋
And when Mademoiselle Daphne from The Merry Shamrock tearooms
打电话给我告诉我奥利弗夫人的行踪时
telephoned to me to inform me of the whereabouts of Madame Oliver,
你在偷听
you were listening in.
我说的没错吧?
Ah, oui, bien s?r.
我挂电话前几秒听到你把听筒放下了
I heard the click as you replaced the telephone receiver a second or two before I did.
你很清楚的知道奥利弗夫人在哪儿
And now you knew exactly where was Madame Oliver.
现在那封信再也不会到警方手中
And now the letter could not longer get into the hands of the police.
现在你的同伙很安全
Now the conspirators were safe.
因此克劳迪娅小姐向警察告发了
Whereupon Mademoiselle Claudia denounced to the police
可怜的诺尔玛・雷斯塔里克小姐
la pauvre Mademoiselle Norma Restarick.
他带我去吃饭逼我这样做的
He took me to dinner and asked me to do it.
他说他无法自己告发自己的亲骨肉
He said he couldn't bring himself to denounce his own flesh and blood.
天呐 诺尔玛 对不起
Oh, God, Norma, I'm so sorry.
都是他的主意!
It was all his idea!
难道你还不懂吗?
Can't you see that?
你演技真拙劣 弗朗西丝 而我也是个笨蛋
You're a terrible actress, Frances. And I'm a fool.
我警告过你 你的仇恨会坏事 但你就是不听
I warned you that your hatred would get in the way, but you wouldn't listen.
小姐
Miss.
弗朗西丝!
Frances!
我们是亲姐妹
We're half-sisters.
看 大卫在罗迪舅父的盒子里发现的
Look, David found it in Uncle Roddy's box.
那是我们的父亲
It's our father.
我看不到有像的地方
I see no resemblance.
我父亲怎么了?
What happened to my father?
我们出城时 发生了一场意外
An accident, while we were up country together.
他是个好伙计 我一直很喜欢他
He was a good chap. I always liked Andrew.
你对这差点被你毁了的可怜人
Have you nothing to say to this poor creature
没什么要说的了吗?
you tried to destroy?
虽然你的心这么黑...
Is there not one impulse that is honest...
你就没有一点诚实吗?
...human, even, in your heart so black?
你想让我说什么?
What would you have me say?
我父亲提到过我吗?
Did... Did my father ever speak of me?
好吧 波罗先生想要诚实
Well, Monsieur Poirot wants honesty...
所以我就实话实说了
...so I'll be honest.
我只听安德鲁提过一次
I only ever heard Andrew mention you once.
他说你就是那个要继承他妻子财产的小贱人
He said you were the little bitch who'd get all his wife's money.
我知道安德鲁已经够坏了
I knew Andrew was rotten,
但你! 你的坏已经无法言表了!
but you! You beggar description!
诺尔玛?
Norma?
这么说索尼娅不是靠色相骗钱财的女人
So, Sonia wasn't a gold-digger after all.
不是
No.
孔雀也不是
Nor was the peacock.
你怎么知道?
How did you know?
因为你告诉过我 夫人
Because you told that to me yourself, madame.
你告诉我说 你看到他对她笑
You told me that you saw him smile at her,
他的目光无法离开她
that he could not take his eyes from hers.
当我意识到他在找家人的照片
And the moment I realised that he was looking for photographs of the family
来证明奥威尔先生是冒牌货的时候
to prove Monsieur Orwell an impostor,
我就知道了
it was then I knew
他是为了诺尔玛小姐好 而不是害她
that he was acting for Mademoiselle Norma and not against her.
- 你确实想了很多事 不是吗? - 啊
- You do think of things, don't you? - Ah.
真是精于算计 弯弯肠子
What a calculating mind. Tortuous,
我会这么说 弯弯肠子
that's what I call it. Tortuous.
我精于算计吗 夫人?
Am I so calculating, madame?
我是个冷血的解谜者吗?
Am I the solver of puzzles with a heart that is cold?
还是我们在看着生活中最大的谜团?
Or are we looking at the greatest of mysteries that life ever throws out?
即使是我赫尔克里・波罗 也无法解释的谜团
The mystery that even I, Hercule Poirot, will never be able to solve.
爱的本质
The nature of love.
她笑了
She smiles.
那是眼泪吗?
Is that a tear?
哦 不 不 不 夫人
Oh, no, no, no, madame.
那是风吹的
It is merely the breeze.
-=ShinY-深影字幕组=-
深影非盈利字幕组诚招特效人员 欢迎大家登陆深影论坛报名
深影字幕组论坛地址 www.gaogebbs.cn                  更多精彩请进http://nbachangsuoyuyan.5d6d.com